<Document>
# Alert Procedure

[head=3][color=#ff0000]Last Updated 14 MAR 2025. THE WIKI IS AUTHORITATIVE. This is intended as an in-game reference only and may be out of date.[/head][/color]

## Green Alert

[italic]"Attention! Station alert level has been set to green! There is currently no known threat to the station, nor its crew. It is safe to return to your workplaces." — Station Announcer Michael[/italic]

- [bold]Chain of Command[/bold]: [textlink="Commanding Officer / Executive Officer" link="Command Hierarchy"] > Departmental Head > Supervisors 
- [bold]Search Procedure[/bold]: Reasonable Suspicion is required for detainment to perform stop & frisk. 
- [bold]Crew Discipline[/bold]: Work within their departments, report for orders from their Departmental Head. 
- [bold]Armoury Procedure[/bold]: Shall not issue lethal longarms; maintain typical Security equipment; non-lethal armament only. 
- [bold]Rules of Engagement[/bold]: Prioritize de-escalation over escalation; Use of Force
- [bold]Secure Areas[/bold]: These places shall not be bolted, allowing access to authorized personnel; areas that require or have an expectation of privacy may be locked. 
- [bold]Medical Staff[/bold]: Ensure crew has binary sensors on, at a minimum.
- [bold]Engineering Staff[/bold]: Ensure station or ship are running smoothly. 

## Blue Alert

[italic]"Attention! Station alert level has been set to blue! There is an on-going, known or suspected security threat to the station or its crew, or another significant security emergency. Crewmembers are advised to follow commands issued by any relevant authority." — Station Announcer Michael[/italic]

- [bold]Chain of Command[/bold]: [textlink="Commanding Officer / Executive Officer" link="Command Hierarchy"] > Head of Security > Warden > Security Personnel > Other Departmental Heads > Supervisors 
- [bold]Search Procedure[/bold]: Probable Cause is Blue Alert itself. Warrants are still required for complete department searches. 
- [bold]Crew Discipline[/bold]: Report suspicious activities to the Departmental Head or Security Personnel. 
- [bold]Armoury Procedure[/bold]: May issue lethal longarms; discretion of the Warden or Head of Security—no open carry of lethal longarms. 
- [bold]Rules of Engagement[/bold]: De-escalate and utilize non-lethals, however lethal force may be used to end a threat. 
- [bold]Secure Areas[/bold]: Certain areas may be bolted, if tampering was found or repeated break-ins. 
- [bold]Medical Staff[/bold]: Ensure the crew has their coordinate sensors activated. Have EVA suits and internals readily available.
- [bold]Engineering Staff[/bold]: Have Hard Suits and have emergency internals readily available. 

## Red Alert

[italic]"Attention! Station alert level has been set to red! There are multiple major emergency situations on-going, or a major security emergency affecting the station. Crewmembers should find a safe place to shelter-in, and are advised ot follow any present authorities." — Station Announcer Michael[/italic]

- [bold]Chain of Command[/bold]: [textlink="Commanding Officer / Executive Officer" link="Command Hierarchy"] > Head of Security > Warden > Security Personnel > Other Departmental Heads > Supervisors 
- [bold]Search Procedure[/bold]: Security may arrest anyone outside of their respective department during Shelter-in-place. Search & Seizure may occur during this time. 
- [bold]Crew Discipline[/bold]: Shelter-in-Place—the Departmental Head [bold]must[/bold] ensure that [bold]all[/bold] their workers are safe from harm. 
- [bold]Armoury Procedure[/bold]: Fully automatic longarms, Hard Suits, and internals at the discretion of the Warden or Head of Security. 
- [bold]Rules of Engagement[/bold]: Lethal Force authorized; use non-lethals on unarmed crew members who interfere with Security operations.  
- [bold]Secure Areas[/bold]: All High-Secure Areas access bolted and guarded. Lockdown in place possible breaching or breached points for the confirmed threat. Bolt and secure these areas with Security presence.  
- [bold]Medical Staff[/bold]: Have a Cryogenic Pod on standby if readily available. Triage Priority: Command & Security Personnel. Emergency responders should prioritize Command & Security. 
- [bold]Engineering Staff[/bold]: Establish a hierarchy of damage mitigation to the station: Secure the Atmospherics, Power Generation Source, and other station or ship components, such as the Grav Gen, from damage or tampering. 

## Yellow Alert

[italic]"Attention! Station alert level has been set to yellow! There is a major issue with atmospheric system, the station has suffered/is about to suffer significant damage, or there is another significant engineering emergency. Crewmembers are advised to stay away from the threat, and stay in their workplaces if necessary." — Station Announcer Michael[/italic]

- [bold]Chain of Command[/bold]: [textlink="Commanding Officer / Executive Officer" link="Command Hierarchy"] > Chief Engineer > Engineering Personnel > Departmental Heads > Supervisors 
- [bold]Search Procedure[/bold]: Reasonable Suspicion is required for detainment to perform stop & frisk. 
- [bold]Crew Discipline[/bold]: Non-engineering personnel are advised to avoid or evacuate affected areas and report to their supervisor or Department Head for orders. Security should aid the Engineering Staff whenever possible. 
- [bold]Armoury Procedure[/bold]: May issue lethal longarms; discretion of the Warden or Head of Security—no open carry of lethal longarms. 
- [bold]Rules of Engagement[/bold]: De-escalate and utilize non-lethals, however lethal force may be used to end a threat. 
- [bold]Secure Areas[/bold]: Ensure that any Engineering portion of the station is safeguarded from further sabotage attempts; Engineering may be locked-down as a whole. 
- [bold]Medical Staff[/bold]: Emergency responders should be suited up and ready to deploy as soon as possible with Hard Suit and Internals. Triage priority: Engineering Staff 
- [bold]Engineering Staff[/bold]: Hard Suits and Internals; distribute emergency internals to crew as needed; propose evacuation procedures if station or ship is deemed irreparable or exceptionally hazardous. 

## Violet Alert

[italic]"Attention! Station alert level has been set to violet! There is a serious viral outbreak, on-going major death event, or there is another significant medical emergency. Crewmembers are advised to distance themselves from others and perform safety measures to prevent further spread." — Station Announcer Michael[/italic]

- [bold]Chain of Command[/bold]: [textlink="Commanding Officer / Executive Officer" link="Command Hierarchy"] > Chief Medical Officer > Medical Personnel > Departmental Heads > Supervisors 
- [bold]Search Procedure[/bold]: Reasonable Suspicion is required for detainment to perform stop & frisk. 
- [bold]Crew Discipline[/bold]: Non-medical personnel should not interfere with medical staff; may assist when called upon— obey all applicable commands from medical personnel. Security should assist medical staff in enforcing quarantine and or medical treatments as necessary. 
- [bold]Armoury Procedure[/bold]: May issue lethal longarms; discretion of the Warden or Head of Security—no open carry of lethal longarms.
- [bold]Rules of Engagement[/bold]: De-escalate and utilize non-lethals, however lethal force may be used to end a threat. 
- [bold]Secure Areas[/bold]: The medical department should be secured by Security to enforce quarantine and ensure medical treatments are enacted. 
- [bold]Medical Staff[/bold]: Emergency responders should be suited up and ready to deploy as soon as possible with Hard Suit and Internals. Triage priority: Medical Staff followed by Command & Security personnel. 
- [bold]Engineering Staff[/bold]: Hard Suits and Internals; distribute emergency internals to crew as needed.

## White Alert

[italic]"Attention! Station alert level has been set to white! The station is suffering dangerously high levels of glimmer, there are several active psionic threats, or there is another significant Epistemic emergency. Turn off all glimmer probers. Seek psionic insulation. Psychics should report for mind breaking." — Station Announcer Michael[/italic]

- [bold]Chain of Command[/bold]: [textlink="Commanding Officer / Executive Officer" link="Command Hierarchy"] > Mystagogue > Psionic Mantis / Epistemics Personnel > Departmental Heads > Supervisors 
- [bold]Search Procedure[/bold]: Reasonable Suspicion is required for detainment to perform stop & frisk. 
- [bold]Crew Discipline[/bold]: Non-epistemic personnel should not interfere with epistemic personnel; may assist when called up— obey all applicable commands from epistemic personnel. Security should assist epistemic staff in apprehending or mind breaking the rogue psionics. 
- [bold]Armoury Procedure[/bold]: May issue lethal longarms; discretion of the Warden or Head of Security—no open carry of lethal longarms.
- [bold]Rules of Engagement[/bold]: Engage with minimal force required; Rules of Engagement on mind breaking is lifted and may be performed by the Psionic Mantis or Mystagogue at their discretion. 
- [bold]Secure Areas[/bold]: The epistemics department should be secured by Security. The glimmer probe or glimmer drain should be secured, and access to it should be limited. 
- [bold]Medical Staff[/bold]: Emergency responders should be suited up and ready to deploy as soon as possible with Hard Suit and Internals. Triage priority: epistemic staff, followed by Command & Security personnel. Have Mindbreaker Toxin readily available. 
- [bold]Engineering Staff[/bold]: Hard Suits and Internals; distribute emergency internals to crew as needed; propose evacuation procedures if station or ship is deemed irreparable or exceptionally hazardous due to a glimmer prober explosion. 

## White Alert Definitions

[bold]Minimum Glimmer (Ψ) level to call code White[/bold]: Ψ450

[bold]Rogue Psionic[/bold] - Anyone who willfully refuses to be mindbroke by avoiding apprehension from the authorities, and or someone who refuses to stop using their power.

[bold]Mindbreaking[/bold] - The act of removing powerful psionic abilities from a person, rendering them inert. 

## Gamma Alert

[italic]"Attention! Station alert level has been set to gamma! Central Command has called the Gamma Alert; the station is on its last legs, almost everyone is dead, or there is another existential crisis affecting the station. Martial Law is now in effect." — Station Announcer Michael[/italic]

- [bold]Chain of Command[/bold]: [textlink="Commanding Officer / Executive Officer" link="Command Hierarchy"] > Head of Security > Security Personnel > Departmental Heads > Supervisors 
- [bold]Search Procedure[/bold]: Invalidated. 
- [bold]Crew Discipline[/bold]: Go immediately to Evacuation Shuttle, Evacuation Pod, Logisics' Cargo Shuttle, or Logistics' Salvage Shuttle. Prioritize your own safety before others to flee imminent danger. Meanwhile, Command may try to reverse the situation or find ways to increase the likelihood of saving their crew from imminent danger. 
- [bold]Armoury Procedure[/bold]: Fully automatic longarms, Hard Suits, and internals at the discretion of the Warden or Head of Security.  
- [bold]Rules of Engagement[/bold]: Security [bold]must[/bold] lethally engage any unknown/known threats to the station and remove them with supreme prejudice. 
- [bold]Secure Areas[/bold]: If permissible, high-secure areas must be safeguarded, sealed, or bolted, and security guards must guard them as a last-ditch effort to prevent station destruction. 
- [bold]Medical Staff[/bold]: Save themselves from immediate danger but treat individuals if it doesn't jeopardize themselves and the person they are treating.
- [bold]Engineering Staff[/bold]: Save themselves from immediate danger but can attempt to patch-up the station to increase the likelihood of allowing other crew to escape. 

## Delta Alert

[italic]"Attention! Station alert level has been set to delta! Station scuttling is imminent, or there is another existential crisis affecting the station. All crew and passengers must be evacuated as applicable. Martial Law is now in effect." — Station Announcer Michael[/italic]

- [bold]Chain of Command[/bold]: [textlink="Commanding Officer / Executive Officer" link="Command Hierarchy"] > Head of Security > Security Personnel > Departmental Heads > Supervisors 
- [bold]Search Procedure[/bold]: Invalidated. 
- [bold]Crew Discipline[/bold]: Go immediately to Evacuation Shuttle, Evacuation Pod, Logisics' Cargo Shuttle, or Logistics' Salvage Shuttle. Prioritize your own safety before others to flee imminent danger. Meanwhile, Command may try to reverse the situation or find ways to increase the likelihood of saving their crew from imminent danger. 
- [bold]Armoury Procedure[/bold]: Fully automatic longarms, Hard Suits, and internals at the discretion of the Warden or Head of Security. Seized contraband weapons and armaments may be used. 
- [bold]Rules of Engagement[/bold]: Security [bold]must[/bold] lethally engage any unknown/known threats to the station and remove them with supreme prejudice.
- [bold]Secure Areas[/bold]: If permissible, high-secure areas must be safeguarded, sealed, or bolted, and security guards must guard them as a last-ditch effort to prevent station destruction. 
- [bold]Medical Staff[/bold]: Save themselves from immediate danger but treat individuals if it doesn't jeopardize themselves and the person they are treating.
- [bold]Engineering Staff[/bold]: Save themselves from immediate danger but can attempt to patch-up the station to increase the likelihood of allowing other crew to escape. 

## Epsilon Alert

[italic]"Attention! Station alert level has been set to epsilon! The Epsilon alert level is now in effect. Consider all contracts terminated." — Station Announcer Michael[/italic]

In-character, you do not know what this entails. This is considered [bold]meta-shielded[/bold]. 

## Generic Definitions

[bold]Lockdown[/bold] — restriction of movement within or access to an area in the interest of safety or health.

[bold]Shelter-in-Place[/bold] — a public safety directive invoked during an emergency; instructing people to find a place of shelter and say there until instructed otherwise.

[bold]Triage[/bold] — sorting and providing treatment to patience and especially combat or disaster victims; assigning a priority order on the basis of where the medical resources can best be used.

[bold]Hierarchy of Controls[/bold] — a method to controlling exposures to hazards via: elimination, substitution, engineering controls, administrative controls, and PPE (personal protective equipment).

[bold]Martial Law[/bold] — replacement of civilian government with military rule and the suspension of civilian legal processes for military power. 

</Document>