<Document>
# Brigging Standard Operating Procedure

[head=3][color=#ff0000]Last Updated 29 MAR 2025. THE WIKI IS AUTHORITATIVE. This is intended as an in-game reference only and may be out of date.[/head][/color]

[bold]The Brig area is under the authority of the Warden.[/bold]

When confining someone inside of the brig, the suspect should be handed to the Warden for processing. It is then the responsibility of the Warden to search, confine, and process the suspect in alignment with sentencing procedures. If the suspect is awaiting trial, then they are to be transferred to the extended confinement area pending a trial. If the Warden is not available, then it is the responsibility of the arresting officer to process the suspect and handle evidence. 

## Treatment of Prisoners

Prisoners have certain rights that [bold]must[/bold] be upheld by security and command personnel. Prisoners must be provided with the following: 

- Adequate medical care and moral, spiritual, or legal counseling if it is requested and available. 
- [italic]These are rights, not grantees.[/italic]
- Access their authorized radio encryption keys only. 
- [italic]This right may be revoked should it be abused.[/italic]
- Clothing, food, and water on request.
- Habitable holding cells or permabrig. 
- [italic]If the secureness and safety of the holding area become compromised, the prisoners must be relocated, until the holding cells or permabrig are returned to a serviceable state.[/italic]
- Freedom of movement within their holding area. 
- [italic]Unless there is an undue risk to life and limb.[/italic]

[head=3]Extended Confinement Prisoners[/head]

Additionally, prisoners in Extended Confinement have certain rights but also more firm restrictions that [bold]must[/bold] be upheld by law enforcement: 

- Only Extended Confinement prisoners may receive visitors. 
- [italic]A maximum of [bold]one individual[/bold] may be permitted to visit a single convict every [bold]10 minutes[/bold]; a reason must be provided for the visit, and the visitor must consent to a search of their belongings.[/italic]
- [italic]Conjugal visits are permitted but limited to no longer than [bold]1 hour[/bold].[/italic]
- Upon approval, prisoners may request supervised work release if the staffing is available.
- Prisoners who intentionally and maliciously cause structural damage to the permabrig, to a degree that makes it unreasonable to hold prisoners within, are thereby guilty of a capital crime.
- Prisoners who intentionally, maliciously, and repeatedly cause significant bodily harm to their fellow inmates, visitors, and/or security staff are thereby guilty of a capital crime.
- Prisoners may request retrial for capital crimes; these requests may be refused depending on the discretion and availability of the court clerk, chief justice, or at the discretion of the warden or head of station security.
- Prisoners may request or may otherwise be given parole with a hearing by the Chief Justice, Court Clerk, or in their absence, the Head of Security or [textlink="commanding officer" link="Command Hierarchy"].

## Preservative Stasis

Should prisoners repeatedly and maliciously antagonize law enforcement, to an extent where continued extended confinement becomes infeasible, two of the three authorized personnel; the Warden, Head of Security, or [textlink="Commanding Officer" link="Command Hierarchy"], may agree to [italic]temporarily[/italic] upgrade the relevant prisoners’ sentences to Preservative Stasis summarily.
-[italic]For more information, check the Preservative Stasis section in Space Law.[/italic]

## Paroles and Pardons

Prisoners may be admitted for parole by the Warden or Head of Security, or may apply for parole at the discretion and availability of the aforementioned parties under the following conditions: 
- Shows peaceful compliance and assists officers with their duties.
- Displays clear signs of remorse concerning the committed crime and/or criminal behaviors.

If parole is requested, they may receive a [textlink="parole hearing" link="Judicial SOP"] conducted by the Court Clerk or Chief Justice, where they will state their case on why they should be released; they may request legal counsel in this hearing, but [bold]must represent themselves.[/bold]

The sentencing officer of an arrest, the judge or arbiter of a trial, or the Warden - for extended confinement prisoners, may pardon members accused or sentenced for crimes if deemed in the best interest of the crew and vessel, and when the circumstances of the defendant or offense warrant suspension of sentence. 


</Document>