<Document>
# Code of Conduct

[head=3][color=#ff0000]Last Updated 12 FEB 2025. THE WIKI IS AUTHORITATIVE. This is intended as an in-game reference only and may be out of date.[/head][/color]

At NanoTrasen, we pride ourselves on maintaining the highest standards of professionalism and respect. As an employee and as a representative of the corporation as a whole, you will be expected to uphold the following company values and ideals: 

## Consideration and Care

Think before you act and ensure you’re acting appropriately and safely. Adhere to company standards, undergo regular training, and follow any safety notices or instructions from authorities. 

## Respect and Collaboration

Treat all colleagues, clients, and members of the public with courtesy and professionalism. Embrace diversity of background and culture, and foster a synergetic work environment. 

## Integrity and Honesty

By acting with integrity and being honest with your colleagues and superiors, you’re upholding the trust placed in you by our customers, our shareholders, and the NanoTrasen brand. Honesty with yourself and others serves the community at large. 

## Confidentiality and Accountability

Safeguard sensitive information about our personnel, clients, company operations, research, and restricted data. Take ownership of this responsibility and the various others assigned to you, and strive for excellence in your work and diligence in your duties. 

## Adaptability and Ingenuity

Embrace change, stay adaptable, and demonstrate a willingness to learn and grow in response to new circumstances. Never quit or give up; show NanoTrasen’s commitment and hard work ethic regardless of any obstacles in your way. 

## Rights and Responsibilities

All general crew aboard NanoTrasen Space Stations have certain rights and responsibilities in order to ensure that the company, its employees, and any customers or the general public are taken into consideration. 

[bold]All members of the crew: [/bold]

Have the right to live in a safe and healthy environment, and to be provided access to necessary safety equipment and medical assistance.

Have the right to be treated with respect and fairness regardless of their role or background.

Have the right to receive clear and accurate information related to their roles, tasks, or relevant updates.

Have the right to receive proper training and development opportunities as necessary to enhance their skills and contribute effectively to company operations.

Have the right to confidentiality regarding personal information and sensitive matters within the bounds of operational requirements.

Have the right to access necessary resources for performing their duties, including equipment, tools, or facilities.

Are responsible for following safety protocols, operating procedures, and company policies to ensure their own safety and others’.

Are responsible for upholding the company’s reputation through their behaviour, communication, and general conduct.

Are responsible for fulfilling their assigned tasks and responsibilities efficiently and to the best of their ability, particularly where they are essential to station function. Are responsible for promptly reporting grievances, hazards, or malfunction to appropriate personnel.

Are responsible for conscientiously managing and utilising their resources for efficient operation. Are responsible for upholding the policies outlined within this CPM14 manual. 

</Document>