<Document>
# Command Hierarchy

[head=3][color=#ff0000]Last Updated 09 MAR 2025. THE WIKI IS AUTHORITATIVE. This is intended as an in-game reference only and may be out of date.[/head][/color]

## Basics

The Captain is the legally appointed officer by Nanotrasen in charge of the station.

However, when they are not present, several steps exist to rectify this until one is assigned to the station or elected.

Here are some definitions, followed by the steps to enable a Chain of Command to follow and obey to ensure that the station runs smoothly from the top down. 

Captain is the formal title, while the legal title is [italic]Commanding Officer[/italic] or [bold]CO[/bold]. The captain's title does not transfer to anyone who has taken the [bold]ID[/bold] unless otherwise stated by Central Command or through other means without Central Command's involvement; i.e., the Captain was removed from their position due to [bold]No Confidence[/bold] or the Captain has died and cannot be revived, or a CO was appointed among the remaining Departmental Heads. 

[italic]Executive Officer,[/italic] or [bold]XO[/bold], is a title appointed by the Captain if they perish and cannot be revived or are missing in action and cannot be recovered through any and all exhaustible means. 

## Situations

[head=3]No XO was appointed when the Captain was present[/head]

Among the departmental heads present, vote and whoever gains majority shall be the Executive Officer; then fax Central Command to be granted authority and take on the mantle as [bold]CO[/bold]. 

[head=3]An XO was appointed when the Captain was present:[/head]

Fax Central Command and inform them of the Captain's untimely demise, and they will [italic]become[/italic] the [bold]CO[/bold]. 

[head=3]There is no CO to lead the Station[/head]

Among the departmental heads present, vote, and whoever gains a majority vote shall be the Executive Officer until a Commanding Officer goes aboard the station, Fax Central Command. The elected XO will be granted access. When a CO arrives, however, they must turn over all effects befitting the legal title and rescind their accesses. 

[head=3]Mutiny and Other Pressing Circumstances[/head]

Conditionally, it will transfer to whoever is elected via a majority vote by the remaining Departmental Heads. 

[head=3]Demotion of Departmental Heads or Executive Officer(s) or Commanding Officer. (Shift-Start Contractor)[/head]

There shall be a majority vote to demote someone for a shift-start Command Member, it should follow similarly to how a Commanding Officer can be removed through [bold]No Confidence[/bold]. Refer to [textlink="Mutiny Guideline" link="Mutiny Guidelines"].

[head=3]Hiring of Departmental Heads[/head]

If there is no Departmental Head at Shift Start, the Commanding Officer or Captain may hire for the Departments that lack a Command member. If there is no CO or Captain, wait unless there's an issue, then go directly to faxing Central Command. 

[head=3]Transfer of Powers and Responsibilities[/head]

If a contracted Departmental Head arrives on the station hired by NanoTrasen, the current On-Shift Hire shall be demoted and all effects shall be turned over to that contracted individual. [italic]If[/italic] the contracted Departmental Head chooses to retain the On-Shift Hire Departmental Head, they can do so and share the responsibilities. 

## A dummy guide to Command Hierarchy

[italic]Written by Quirin Inanis - regional grumpy CMO[/italic]

[head=3]What is a CO?[/head]

[bold]CO[/bold] [italic](Commanding Officer)[/italic] is a title that means you are the one in Command; you're at the top! [bold]By default the role of Captain has this title![/bold] But in some circumstances this can change. Being the CO means you need to lead, so make sure you're comfortable being under pressure! [italic](CO also often comes with nice perks like AA and getting to tell the Heads what to do)[/italic] 

[head=3]What is the XO?[/head]

[bold]XO[/bold] [italic](Executive Officer)[/italic] is a title appointed by the [bold]Captain[/bold]. It does nothing on it's own, until the Command Hierarchy changes in some way! 

[head=3]How is the title of CO moved?[/head]

In the case that there is no Captain [italic](unrecoverably dead, no one playing the role, missing, etc.)[/italic] the title of CO will be handed down. [bold]Note: Any change in the CO title needs to be Faxed to CC. If the Captain appointed an XO, they are now the new CO![/bold] Otherwise the Department heads vote among themselves which one becomes the new CO. This is often reffered to as being the "Acting CO". [bold]Note that this is temporary![/bold] If a Captain shows up again, they take back the title of CO and everything that comes with it! The Captain can also loose the title of CO in some ways, either if a higher-up from Nanotrasen shows up, or if there was a [bold]No Confidence vote[/bold]. [italic](Go look at the rules for Mutiny for more on that)[/italic]

[head=3]What if a Head is missing?[/head]

If a Deparment doesn't have a Head [italic](unrecoverably dead, no one playing, missing, etc.)[/italic] a new [bold]temporary Head is appointed by the CO from among that Departments staff[/bold]. Same as with the CO title, if a Head does end up showing up all the power, items, etc. are transfered back to them. [italic](If the Department Head wants someone to share the load, they can choose to not Demote the replacement Head to work together, how sweet)[/italic]

[head=3]What if there is absolutely no command staff? (Meaning no one can take the title of CO)[/head]

Nothing! Just wait! If there is [bold]some issue: Fax Central Command![/bold]

</Document>