<Document>
# Engineering Standard Operating Procedure

[head=3][color=#ff0000]Last Updated 22 MAR 2025. THE WIKI IS AUTHORITATIVE. This is intended as an in-game reference only and may be out of date.[/head][/color]

## Special Projects, Demolition, and Renovations

Engineering has the right to control, manage, and issue permits for building, renovation, or demolishing portions of the station, with the Chief Engineer having the final say or applicable CO (i.e., the Captain.)

    [italic]If the engineering department does not have enough people to provide an Engineering Tech, Technical Assistant, or Atmospheric Technician to any of the above, ensure that there is a simple form that outlines what is to be done to the area, i.e., 'Renovating the Bar to make it a strip club,' or 'Demolishing a defunct part of Security and make it a lounge,' or 'Building a sauna attached to medical,' and ensure that it is [bold]stamped and approved[/bold].[/italic]

## Engineering Tools

The Engineering Department [italic]should not[/italic] distribute special [bold]engineering[/bold] tools unless given express permission by the Chief Engineer or CO, e.g., giving insulated gloves and welding goggles to a Passenger or Magnetic Boots to Security Officers. 

[head=3]Special Conditions for Engineering Tools[/head]

Unless noted otherwise, Engineers and Atmos Techs can dispense engineering tools to other departments that need them, e.g., Epistemics and Logistics. [bold]Technical Assistants shall not dispense tools except when told by someone with seniority.[/bold] Engineering [italic]shall[/italic] provide [bold]Epistemics[/bold] with these specialized tools, which required for artifact or anomalous research. Engineering [italic]shall[/italic] provide Logistics [bold]Salvagers[/bold] with specialized tools, such as insulated gloves and welding goggles, to prevent grievous injury from space wreckage. 

## Atmospherics & Gas Generation

The Engineering Department [italic]may[/italic] produce experimental, hard-to-obtain gasses such as Frezon and Tritium for the purpose of selling, or approved experimentation, or power generation or safeguarding the station (Supermatter Safed out via Frezon to crash it and prevent a [bold]Delamination Event[/bold]). 

</Document>