<Document>
# Epistemics Standard Operating Procedure

[head=3][color=#ff0000]Last Updated 20 MAR 2025. THE WIKI IS AUTHORITATIVE. This is intended as an in-game reference only and may be out of date.[/head][/color]

## Research & Distribution of Experimental Technology

 Epistemics in general has the right to refuse or allow the distribution of experimental technology under the permission of the respective Department Head requesting the experimental equipment or technology.

    [italic]For example, the Chief Engineer gives the word or provides a written statement requesting Epistemics distribute experimental Engineering tools to the Engineering crew, or the Mystagogue approves of all Epistemics using and distributing speed boots to their department.[/italic]

This does not mean that a Departmental Head is strictly beholden to this baseline standard; understand that as Command, they [italic]should[/italic] have an acute understanding of the [italic]consequences[/italic] of distributing experimental equipment.

The Mystagogue has final say on what can be [bold]freely distributed[/bold], within reason. 

## Dispensation of 'Experimental' equipment

Epistemics workers and researchers [italic]should use[/italic] [bold]discretion[/bold] when issuing certain pieces of experimental equipment.

    [italic]It is [bold]not[/bold] reasonable for Epistemics to mass-produce weapons or explosives of any kind unless under direct orders by the Captain or CO.[/italic]

    [italic]It [bold]is[/bold] reasonable that Epistemics may dispense experimental equipment that provides Quality of Life improvements for the station's many roles, such as the Advanced Mop, Bluespace Beakers, and Mining Drills, as examples.[/italic]

    [italic]For further information on what is considered contraband (do not give it out without approval or produce it and ensure you have a [textlink="Permit" link="Permits"]), refer to Controlled Items and Substances (TODO: Add link)[italic]

[head=3]Use discretion[/head]
(Adapted from wiki)

[italic]Advanced Mop, Mega Spray Bottle:[/italic] Free-to-Distribute

[italic]Jaws of Life, Drill, Experimental Welder:[/italic] [bold]Contraband[/bold], Permit Required + Departmental Head Approval

[italic]Mining Drills, Bluespace Ore Bag:[/italic] Free-to-Distribute

[italic]Bluespace Beaker:[/italic] Free-to-Distribute

[italic]Svallin Laser + Other Weaponry:[/italic] [bold]Contraband[/bold], Permit Required + Departmental Head Approval

## Research & Experimentations

Epistemics workers and researchers should refrain from experimenting on themselves, or pursuing dangerous artifact research methods, such as using [bold]Artifexium[/bold] on-station with multiple alien artifacts, as that endangers the crew and station.

    [italic]This method should be used off-station with a purpose-built area. Typical, single artifact research is exempt from this for obvious reasons.[/italic]

Epistemics [italic]should[/italic] issue Logistics with an expedition board at their [italic]discretion[/italic] and industrial ore processor when readily available.

    [italic]This means you should think before issuing that solo Salvager an Expedition Board.[/italic]

Epistemics [italic]should[/italic] safeguard the Protolathe and Circuit Board Printer to prevent misuse to a reasonable degree.

    [italic]This means that you should think about the possibilities of endangerment and understand that [bold]you[/bold] as the decision maker at the time, may be liable. Please remember to do the paperwork to reduce the likelihood of Security hassling you.[/italic]

## IPCs & Cybernetics

Epistemics shall provide services to all crew IPCs and Cyborgs, such as upgrades, battery replacements, and repairs.  

    [italic]This means they should be freely given higher-end batteries as they become available.[/italic]

Epistemics shall ask before creating Cyborgs for departments; otherwise, create typical Cyborg frames (Quad or Regular) instead of Specialized ones, such as the Engineering or Medical Borgs.

</Document>