<Document>
# General Regulations

[head=3][color=#ff0000]Last Updated 01 MAR 2025. THE WIKI IS AUTHORITATIVE. This is intended as an in-game reference only and may be out of date.[/head][/color]

## Right to Refuse Service

All standard [bold]Service[/bold] and [bold]Logistics[/bold] members working in a secure area have the [italic]right to refuse service[/italic] to patrons when found to be [bold]abusive or disorderly[/bold]. The use of non-lethal force is permitted to remove these individuals from the area if they [bold]pose a risk[/bold] to the staff of the secure area [bold]or[/bold] disrupt the function of the services provided. Essentially, do not attempt to break in or jump the counter to take things that are not for you.

- [italic]You've been reported to Security for being abusive and demanding of the Cargo Technicians. [/italic]
- [italic]You've been told to leave, but refuse to do so, and thus you receive a ban from the location until you apologize. [/italic]
- [italic]After all levels of attempted de-escalation, you've nonetheless been beaten to near death because you decided to jump the counter to try and snatch materials that were not yours. Shame on you. [/italic]

[head=3]Additional Conditions[/head]

The Bar(s) and Maintenance Bar(s) can have additional rules dictated by who is currently running the establishment; they have the authority to carry these out so long as it does not needlessly over-escalate or have draconian requirements to be followed. A few examples of a rule within the bar: 

- [italic]You may be asked to leave, if intimate relations at the bar are disrupting the general tame atmosphere. [/italic]
- [italic]You may be asked to leave, if you become a depressive drunk, and becoming belligerent. [/italic]
- [italic]You may be asked to leave, if you do not meet the requirements of a dress code or no dress code. [/italic]

## Hiring & Termination Procedure

Currently, NanoTrasen dictates who is brought in during shift changes and where they are placed within the respective departments; however, when there are staffing shortages, the Departmental Head or Commanding Officer may offer an additional contract to anyone interested in filling in any gaps in a department. An acting command member can be hired this way, as well. Check that people becoming employed for the department have experience; [bold]ask, don't assume[/bold]. Finally, ensure they're given signed and stamped paperwork stating their job change and who approved it. 

A department head or acting department head can be terminated, much like any other worker on the station. Conditions include, but are not limited to, [bold]theft, sabotage, misuse of department accesses and/or tools, negligence, and refusing to do their job title's tasks and role aboard the station.[/bold]

A worker's right to refuse work outside of the job title's scope is [italic]NOT[/italic] grounds for termination. [bold]What should be done is to ask if they are interested in adding more to their tasks and roles, i.e.[/bold]

- "Are they reasonably trained and understand the role?"
- "Do they already have more than enough on their plate?"
- "Should I assign more responsibility to someone who's already busy?"
- "Should I instead, hire someone outside of the department for assistance?"

Finally, [bold]if the new hire is part of Security or Command[/bold], please make sure that they are given a [bold]Mindshield as it is part of any Security or Command contract[/bold]; refusal to be Mindshielded means they will not be employed. 

## Presentation of Identification (ID)

All crewpersons on the station should have their identification, readily available to present to anyone who requires it. 

</Document>