<Document>
# Permits

[head=3][color=#ff0000]Last Updated 16 FEB 2025. THE WIKI IS AUTHORITATIVE. This is intended as an in-game reference only and may be out of date.[/head][/color]

## The Issuer

Below is a table of who can issue what classification of controlled substance or item within the department.

It is not reasonable for a Chief Engineer to give a Doctor a permit to provide prescribed desoxyephedrine, but the Chief Engineer can give the Doctor a permit for power tools for whatever reason.

Whereas, the Captain has the absolute authority to issue a permit and revoke it for any reason. 

(Adapted from wiki table due to formatting limitations)
- Captain/Commanding Officer: Class 1/2/3
- Head of Security/Warden/Security: Class 1/2 only
- Mystagogue/Epistemics: Class 2 only
- Chief Engineer/Engineering: Class 2 only
- Head of Personnel/Service: Class 2 only
- Chief Medical Officer/Medical: Class 2 only
- Logistics Officer/Logistics: N/A

## Reasonings

Above as majority of Class 1 things are typically weapons of low grade and caliber, and almost majority, if not all of substances would fall under Class 2. It is reasonable to surmise that most of departments cannot and will not issue permits for this; easiest method to gain a permit is Security, or Medical.

Epistemics and Engineering can give out specialized tools and should issue permits with it.

Not all departmental heads have purview over controlled substances and items, though the Service Department and Head of Personnel are allowed to grow certain medicinal plants. 

## The permit

A weapon license can be issued from Security; it must be signed and stamped by the permit issuer.

A prescribed medicine can be issued from Medical; it must be signed and stamped by the permit issuer.

A building permit can be issued from Engineering; it must be signed and stamped by the permit issuer.

Above are simple examples, the Captain or Commanding Officer, can issue these permits, however, a crew person should seek out the department or the Departmental Head for the appropriate permit to lessen the strain on the Captain or Commanding Officer.

For cross-departmental permits, such as a weapons permit or license for Salvage, the Logistics Officer can initiate the permit process, put down what the Salvagers need captured on the permit and Security signs it and stamps it for approval.

Departmental Heads must not sign and stamp their own permits if it's for something outside of their department. They may only do so for items and substances they have control over. 

[italic]It doesn't have to be anything fancy, as long as the conditions are met: Department it was issued from, the name of the permit issuer, the name of the permit receiver, and a signed name and stamped approve or departmental stamp.[/italic]

## Defiance of Permit

At any time, as mentioned above, a permit can be recinded due to the commission of a crime, or other extenuating factors, such as Alert Procedure affecting it. There are many conditions that cannot be outlined, but if a simple example would be that someone has a Class 2 object in their possession but not listed on their Permit. Ensure that both parties know what they are writing down. 

</Document>