<Document>
# Self-Defence

[head=3][color=#ff0000]Last Updated 12 FEB 2025. THE WIKI IS AUTHORITATIVE. This is intended as an in-game reference only and may be out of date.[/head][/color]

NanoTrasen prioritizes the safety and well-being of all individuals aboard its space stations, including employees and patrons. The company recognises that maintaining a secure environment is essential to operations, and, in light of this fact, all NanoTrasen employees are authorised to exercise their right to self-defence when confronted with an imminent threat of physical harm or violence upon their person.

This is a clear demonstration of our unwavering support for your safety and well-being, under these guidelines:

The threat must be immediate and serious, with clear intent to cause grievous harm or injury to the employee.

Before resorting to self-defence, the employee must have exhausted all reasonable alternatives for avoiding or escaping the threat - including following established protocols, attempting de-escalation, and seeking assistance from security personnel.

The response to the threat must be proportional to the level of danger posed; that is, the employee must only use the force necessary to protect themselves from harm.

The employee’s primary directive is to ensure their own safety. Once the opportunity to escape arises, or the threat is neutralised, the employee must cease their use of force and immediately seek assistance from security personnel, medical staff, and any other relevant authorities.

In any situation where an employee exercises self-defence against any individual aboard the station, they must provide a detailed account of the incident, including the circumstances immediately prior, to their immediate supervisor, security personnel, or station administration, where applicable and at their earliest convenience.

[bold]The authorization for self-defence is an exceptional measure intended to address extreme situations where no other viable options exist and only to facilitate a secure environment that fosters collaboration, innovation, and mutual respect between NanoTrasen’s employees.[/bold]

</Document>