<Document>
[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 11: Antagonists[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c]11.1[/color] Antagonistic roles are held to a higher standard of roleplay. 

[color=#a4885c]11.2[/color] Damage by any antagonist role must be proportional to their related objectives, and be pertinent to their objectives. Rarely if ever, station-wide destruction and mass killing is justifiable. Ask an Admin via AHelp if you are unsure of whether the level of damage you want to cause is acceptable or not. 

[color=#a4885c]11.3[/color] Antagonists must follow a 30 minutes grace period from round start. 

[color=#a4885c]11.4[/color] Do not intentionally round remove (gibbing, ashing, etc.) another player without their OOC consent, unless it happens purely and clearly by accident or by unintended consequence (barred obvious round-ending exceptions such as nukies managing to detonate the nuke or blood cultist managing to complete the ritual, which will cause other players to be "round removed"). 

[color=#a4885c]11.5[/color] Playing a normally hostile ghost role as a friendly is permitted. However, it is strongly advised to seek permission from an admin if you wish to do so. This way, the admin may help in clarifying your friendly status. Else, you will be liable for being killed or attacked on sight (so long of course proper escalation, reasoning and roleplay is followed by the attacker). Furthermore, by making this choice, you are forbidden from switching back to playing it as an hostile role without extremely good motive, and are also forbidden from faking being friendly. 

[color=#a4885c]11.6[/color] The role of an antagonist is to make the game more fun, exciting and interesting, not miserable, unfun and frustrating. As such, try to play out the role accordingly, focusing not on winning, but on making things more thrilling and entertaining. 

[color=#a4885c]11.7[/color] Antagonists should refrain from collaborating unless they belong to the same faction and do have an actual mutual deal established. For example, a nuclear operative and an agent may collaborate, so long within terms such as, an operative helping an agent to complete one or more objectives, and in turn them helping with acquiring the nuke and the disk (but not staying behind after countdown begins to ensure it goes off, since the nuke is not their primary objective and they should be coming back alive).
</Document>