<Document>
  olor=#ffff00][head=3]Section 5: Roleplay and Characters[/head][/color]

  [color=#a4885c]5.1[/color] You are expected to roleplay, and maintain a good level and quality of roleplay. As such, focusing solely on "winning" (such as greentexting) is strongly discouraged. So is questionable behavior unfit for an organized, civilized system and society (such as but not limited to: distribution of highly dangerous items without strict need, emergency or valid motive, casually allowing strangers in your department, casual destruction of station property etc.)

  [color=#a4885c]5.2[/color] Prioritize making the game fun for everyone, not just yourself. Security, Command and antagonist roles are held to a higher standard and scrutiny, especially if their actions are found to be going against this rule. Ask an Admin via AHelp if you are unsure of whether or not the idea you got in mind might be pushing too much the acceptable boundaries.

  [color=#a4885c]5.3[/color] Your character is a separate entity from you, the player. Your character's actions, feelings, and knowledge in-game should be based solely on the character's experiences rather than your own as the player. Also, do keep in mind that while your character may be the main character of your story, they are not the protagonist at the center of everything.

  [color=#a4885c]5.4[/color] Do not make yourself a major problem, annoyance, or disruption for the crew while not being an antagonist (i.e. self-antagging or griefing). Examples may include: random murder, destruction or disruption, stealing of high caliber items (such as Security weapons or Command items), or intentional sabotage.

  [color=#a4885c]5.5[/color] Do not play excessively hostile or provocative characters. Playing a character accurately should never result in rule breaches. Being a major nuisance or a source of major frustration to the crew, or behaving in a way that is affecting very negatively the laid-back environment we intend to maintain, is not accepted. If you are unsure or got a particular idea, ask in AHelp for approval.

  [color=#a4885c]5.6[/color] Follow proper escalation (for example, consider assessing a threat for a second before unloading lethal rounds into it, attempt an arrest with non-lethals before opening fire with lethals on someone, and don't use lethal force on someone or something out of the blue without reasonable motive or emergency). Security roles in particular are asked to mind this rule.

  [color=#a4885c]5.7[/color] Do not loot AFK players, nor round remove their bodies without consent, outside of reasonable exceptions (biomassing previous bodies of cloned players, Security performing their duties, etc.).

  [color=#a4885c]5.8[/color] Dismantling, scrapping or destruction of station property without a reasonable emergency, urgency or need for it is strongly discouraged (such as for example, dismantling tables and chairs around the station or an escape pod just for its materials and parts).

  [color=#a4885c]5.9[/color] Players should always try to bring crew members that are found dead or critically injured to the appropriate department (or to the next best location if unavailable) for treatment, such as Medical or Epistemics. Do not ignore, hide, or destroy their body. This applies for station pets as well, (the animals with unique names, and friendly creatures who are given pet status by the HoP), who are also considered as part of the crew.

  [color=#a4885c]5.10[/color] If, when and where possible, always try to do things in a roleplay-friendly way and keep the roleplay rolling. For example, for controversial matters (such as firing an Head), consider contacting CentCom first before immediately AHelping (unless it's for a major rule violation, or unless you are not receiving any answer back from CentCom).

  [color=#a4885c]5.11[/color] Players are allowed and even encouraged to engage in creative gimmicks, mischief, hijinks and ideas, so long it doesn't cross the border into unacceptable behavior (self-antag, powergaming, metagaming, etc.) and so long properly and well roleplayed. Examples of acceptable ideas could be, light greytiding, well roleplayed hooliganism, breaking into places with good RP or motive, thievery, or black marketing.

  [color=#a4885c]5.12[/color] When picking the name for a character, give them a believable name (and surname if applicable), or a believable nickname to go by. Do not make obvious references, puns, or plays on words. You may "cosplay" a fictional character, but you cannot be the character. Leeway is given to theatrical roles such as the clown, boxer, and mime; these roles are allowed stage names with some more freedom.

  [color=#a4885c]5.13[/color] Suicide RP is forbidden.
</Document>
