<Document>
  [color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 8: End-of-Round (EOR) and Evacuation[/head][/color]

  [color=#a4885c]8.1[/color] Disruptive behavior in end-of-round Safe Havens (such as the evacuation shuttle and Central Command) is forbidden. This includes but is not limited to: damaging property, intentionally blocking pathways to prevent other players from passing through, fighting, etc. During evacuation or crew transfer, the evacuation boarding areas and hallways directly next to the evacuation shuttle are considered part of the Safe Haven as well.

  [color=#a4885c]8.2[/color] Conflicts in End-Of-Round Safe Havens must remain verbal and non-violent. Exception is made for Security, who may perform arrests non-lethally.

  [color=#a4885c]8.3[/color] In a Safe Haven, lethal force may only be used for threats that cannot be stopped in any other way. This generally only applies to hostile NPCs and self defense.

  [color=#a4885c]8.4[/color] Antagonist roles are allowed to pursue non-violent objectives in a non-violent way in Safe Havens. However, if caught, they must not resist arrest and surrender.

  [color=#a4885c]8.5[/color] Evac should be called or recalled based on either general public consensus, or under whether a major, serious emergency is being deemed as solvable or not. Forcefully calling or recalling without reasonable urgency, emergency or need is not allowed. Consider calling ERT, CBURN or other such entities first, and if you receive no response or they fail as well, proceed to call evac. For example, calling evac just because Nukies showed up is bad practice, but serious hard to repair structural damage to the station or most Security becoming KIA, are pretty sound motives.

  [color=#a4885c]8.6[/color] Antagonists are not allowed to call nor recall evac. Intentionally disrupting evac, such as parking or hovering a ship at or near the area where normally evac arrives for the purpose of forcing evac to dock elsewhere, is not allowed. Some exceptions may be allowed, but require explicit administrator approval.

</Document>
