<Document>
[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 9: Erotic-Role-Play (ERP) Rules[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]9.1[/color] Make your consent menu specific. Include information such as Gender preferences, sexual orientation, kinks you like or dislike, non negotiable as well as any non sexual physical contact preferences. *1

[color=#a4885c]9.2[/color] ERP does not take priority over your job. If you are requested or needed, you must respond or return to your duties ASAP. *1

[color=#a4885c]9.3[/color] DO NOT use ERP as bait for kill objectives, unless done with OOC consent of all parties involved. After the ERP is complete, a grace period of 5 minutes is in effect, during which you are still NOT allowed to kill the target. *1

[color=#a4885c]9.4[/color] Do not kinkshame. *1

[color=#a4885c]9.5[/color] You MUST use the (-) subtle command for any and all erotic roleplay material. *1

[color=#a4885c]9.6[/color] Do not spam or pollute radio channels (including the telepath channel) with NSFW topics. Mind you, this does NOT mean that you are not allowed to speak or discuss such. There should not be a cringy spamfest of: shitposting, hornyposting, or depression posting. *1

[color=#a4885c]9.7[/color] Do not engage in, nor discuss, ‘extreme’ sexual fetishes in public. Public includes: any radio channel (including the telepath channel), out loud speech or overt actions in actual public physical locations, or doing so on camera. *1

[color=#a4885c]9.8[/color][color=#f1c232] Engaging in ERP with a non-sentient creature is prohibited. The creature must be player-controlled; consent in OOC, and pass the Harkness test in character. *2[/color]

[color=#a4885c]9.9[/color][color=#f1c232] As a Paradox anomaly, OOC consent from the original (the owner of said character) is required before you engage in ERP. *2[/color]

[color=#a4885c]9.10[/color][color=#cc0000] Roleplaying a character as underage is strictly forbidden. So is talk of such activities. *3[/color]

[color=#a4885c]9.11[/color][color=#cc0000] Be very mindful of in-character and out-of-character consent. If your (out-of-character) OOC consent is not respected, immediately Ahelp or open a ticket. *3[/color]

[color=#a4885c]9.12[/color][color=#cc0000] Extreme acts like snuff, abuse, noncon, and other extreme kinks are only allowed if all parties consented OOC, Ahelp if you need clarification (Keep it private). *3[/color]
</Document>
