<Document>
  [color=#a4885c]9.1[/color] Be very mindful of in-character and out-of-character consent. If your (out-of-character) OOC consent is not respected, immediately Ahelp or open a ticket.

  [color=#a4885c]9.2[/color] Make your consent menu specific. Include information such as Gender preferences, sexual orientation, kinks you like or dislike, non negotiable as well as any non sexual physical contact preferences.

  [color=#a4885c]9.3[/color] DO NOT use ERP as bait for kill objectives, unless done with OCC consent of all parties involved. After the ERP is complete, a grace period of 5 minutes is in effect, during which you are still NOT allowed to kill the target.

  [color=#a4885c]9.4[/color] ERP does not take priority over your job. If you are requested or needed, you must respond or return to your duties ASAP.

  [color=#a4885c]9.5[/color] You MUST use the (-) subtle command for any erotic roleplay material.

  [color=#a4885c]9.6[/color] Do not spam or pollute radio channels (including the telepath channel) with NSFW topics. Mind you, this does NOT mean that you are not allowed to speak or discuss such. There should not be a cringy spamfest of: shitposting, hornyposting, or depression posting.

  [color=#a4885c]9.7[/color] Do not engage in, nor discuss, ‘extreme’  sexual fetishes in public. Public includes: any radio channel (including the telepath channel), out loud speech or overt actions in actual public physical locations, or doing so on camera.

  [color=#a4885c]9.8[/color] Do not kinkshame.

  [color=#a4885c]9.9[/color] Roleplaying a character as underage is strictly forbidden. So is talk of such activities.

  [color=#a4885c]9.10[/color] Engaging in ERP with a feral, non-sentient creature is prohibited. The creature must be player-controlled; consent in OOC, and pass the Harkness test in character.

  [color=#a4885c]9.11[/color] Extreme acts such as killing, severely maiming, nonconning, abuse, or even round removal are allowed, so long that all the participants consented OOC, Ahelp if you need clarification (Keep it private).
</Document>
