<Document>
[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 4: Powergaming[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c]4.1[/color] Do not powergame (i.e. minmaxing to try and achieve the best possible results to the point of being detrimental to roleplay, rushing to acquire strong or useful equipment you do not need, pulling all sorts meta tricks and exploits that are unfair or unfit for a roleplay environment, and so forth). 

[color=#a4885c]4.2[/color] Do not rush for, hoard, or prepare equipment unrelated to your job or that you do not need. If you, in your given role, require items that do not fall within your job’s usual parameters or that you do not necessarily need, seek in-character roleplay-friendly methods and/or explanations to obtain them and as for why you need or want them. "Greytiding" is allowed so long not performed to an unreasonable degree.

[color=#a4885c]4.3[/color] Manufacturing dangerous, powerful or/and out of the norm items such as weapons, bombs, deadly poisons, specialized machinery, or obstructive structures without reasonable emergency or need, is liable to be considered powergaming behavior. If you are unsure or got a particular idea, ask in AHelp for approval. Seek in-character roleplay-friendly methods and/or explanations to obtain them and as for why you need or want them outside of emergency or strict need.

[color=#a4885c]4.4[/color] As a non-antagonist, do not intentionally hide antagonist objective items, especially in impossible-to-see/access locations. You may hide items somewhere inside of the room they are located in, or on your character. If you are an antagonist, avoid stealing things you do not necessarily need that maybe another antagonist may need. 

[color=#a4885c]4.5[/color] While it is allowed for the crew to know the details around the various antagonist functions, it is forbidden to act on that information without valid motive (for example, evidence strongly suggesting them being an antagonist, or reliable witnesses of a serious crime), and you are always to presume innocence until proven guilty. For example, you shouldn't check PDAs, implants, and headsets, unless there is enough evidence or motive to assume the person is an antagonist. Refer to the SOP for details.

[color=#a4885c]4.6[/color] Do not validhunt (i.e to hunt, pursue, antagonize and otherwise go out of your way to engage an antagonist with hostile intent). Non-Security personnel should not actively seek out and try to attack, detain or kill antagonists and hostile NPCs that are not threatening you immediately. Notable exceptions being, temporary emergency conscription as Security personnel, or endorsement and sanctioning by a Security Officer (or higher, including any Command member as temporary CO in the event Captain, HoS or Warden are KIA) in a serious emergency (for example, rallying the crew to help if most of Security becomes KIA).

[color=#a4885c]4.7[/color] Do not exploit game mechanics, bugs, tricks or unintended features to circumvent roleplay, to make things much easier for you and more unfair for others, or in any malicious capacity. For example, cryo, ghost and death mechanics (i.e antag-rolling, hiding in cryo to escape from Security, ghosting solely to fish for antagonist roles, etc.).

[color=#a4885c]4.8[/color] Do not intentionally breach nor metagame roleplay in order to gain unfair advantages (such as, engaging someone in combat when they are busy typing something out directed to you, or fake typing to bait somebody to get closer). 

[color=#a4885c]4.9[/color] Do not dismantle or damage important, irreplaceable station infrastructure. If you are unsure or got a particular idea, ask in AHelp for approval. 

[color=#a4885c]4.10[/color] Try to avoid minmaxing to the point of it becoming a detriment to your job or to roleplay, if not prevent you from doing either or even outright putting people in danger. You don't necessarily need to wait for an advanced ore processor before starting to provide materials to the station as Logistics, and you don't necessarily need to wait for an advanced anomaly vessel before starting to do anomalies as Epistemics. 

[color=#a4885c]4.11[/color] Station departments are expected to be working together and collaborating. Avoid self-isolating "independency" tactics and behaviors (for example, Salvage hoarding what they found instead of distributing the excess, or/and going fully independent, or Epistemics/Logistics acquiring machines that would skip interactions with other departments because it's more "efficient").
</Document>