<Document>
[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 7: Death and New Life[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c]7.1[/color] Players maintain all in character memory up until the point of going into their unconscious/critical health state. 

[color=#a4885c]7.2[/color] If a player is brought back to life by any means that is not cloning or similar, they may only retain vague details of the events leading up to their death, and none in relation to the killer, their method, and how it specifically went down. For example, if hypopenned or stabbed to death, they may remember stinging, but not specifically that they got hypopenned or stabbed, nor by who. If they died by a poisoned burger, they may remember eating a burger. If they got killed by a nukie after knowing already a nukie is on board, they can easily assume they got killed by said nukie, but only have a vague recollection of the details leading up to their death. 

[color=#a4885c]7.3[/color] If a player is brought back to life by means of cloning (or similar methods implying new life in a new brain), they lose all of the memories that have been acquired so far into shift. 

[color=#a4885c]7.4[/color] Characters do not retain any knowledge of what happened while they were dead. As such, usage and/or in-character relaying of information gained while dead is forbidden and also considered a metagaming violation. 

[color=#a4885c]7.5[/color] Characters only retain vague memories of what happened while in a critical state, asleep, or generally unconscious (i.e. remembering hearing the radio crackle while asleep, remembering feeling their PDA being touched while crit, etc.). 

[color=#a4885c]7.6[/color] 7.6 If your character dies or enters cryostasis beyond the point of no return, you normally cannot respawn as the same character. Seek permission from an admin if you need or wish to do so. The only allowed exception being, if you accidentally spawn as the wrong character or job, and so immediately cryo to rejoin with the right one. At this moment, personnel recovery forms are also accepted if submitted to CC as a way for other players to ask admins to allow a character to respawn.
</Document>