<Document>
[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 8: End-of-Round (EOR) and Evacuation[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c]8.1[/color] Disruptive behavior in end-of-round Safe Havens (such as the evacuation shuttle and Central Command) is forbidden. This includes but is not limited to: damaging property, intentionally blocking pathways to prevent other players from passing through, fighting, etc. During evacuation or crew transfer, the evacuation boarding areas and hallways directly next to the evacuation shuttle are considered part of the Safe Haven as well. 

[color=#a4885c]8.2[/color] Conflicts in End-Of-Round Safe Havens must remain verbal and non-violent. Exception is made for Security, who may perform arrests non-lethally. 

[color=#a4885c]8.3[/color] In a Safe Haven, lethal force may only be used for threats that cannot be stopped in any other way. This generally only applies to hostile NPCs and self defense. 

[color=#a4885c]8.4[/color] Antagonist roles are allowed to pursue non-violent objectives in a non-violent way in Safe Havens. However, if caught, they must not resist arrest and surrender. 

[color=#a4885c]8.5[/color] Evac should not be called nor recalled without reasonable motive. Outside of emergencies, Command should consult the station inhabitants first and follow their will based on majority vote. During emergencies, alternative methods should be sought first to try and deal with the situation at hand (ERT, CBURN, emergency conscription, etc.), and evac should be called only when all other options have been exhausted or/and when can be reasoned there are no better alternatives or ways available to deal with the situation (for example, serious unrepairable or extremely hard to repair damage to the station or its inhabitants). An antagonist simply showing up is usually not a good reason to call evac alone.

[color=#a4885c]8.6[/color] Antagonists are not allowed to call nor to recall evac, nor interfer with the process. Intentionally or forcibly disrupting evac, such as parking or hovering a ship at or near the area where normally evac arrives or destroying the evac docks, for the purpose of causing evac to dock elsewhere, is not allowed either; nor is faking multiple votes for a shuttle call/recall by voice mask. Some exceptions may be allowed (such as recalling to allow certain specific antags such as revolutionaries or nukies to be able to finish their mission), but require explicit administrator approval.
</Document>