<Document>
  [color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 10: Command and Security[/head][/color]

  [color=#a4885c]10.1[/color] Security and Command roles must know how to perform their job to the best of their ability, and are held to a higher standard of roleplay. This does not mean they must roleplay strict and realistic, but merely that higher quality roleplay, skill and sensible reasoning is expected.

  [color=#a4885c]10.2[/color] Command, and especially Security, are required to know Security Standard Operating Procedures, Alert Procedure, and Company Policy, and are expected to try and follow them to the best of their abilities. Some leniency is given to: Cadets, in reason of it being a learning role; general breaches performed in dire emergency (plus minor general breaches happening under good quality roleplay); and Company Policy, some parts of which do not necessarily need to be strictly followed (such as dressing code, formalities and the likes).

  [color=#a4885c]10.3[/color] Do not abuse your position of power (unless this is being done privately and with consent of all parties involved).

  [color=#a4885c]10.4[/color] As a Command member, you are to adhere to your responsibilities and duties. Prioritize the needs and wants of the station, not only those of your own or of your friends. This especially applies during emergencies and crisis situations.

  [color=#a4885c]10.5[/color] Use lethals and lethal force within reason. As per SOP, arrest with non-lethals if possible, proceed with lethals if not. If you do not have a reasonable urgency, emergency or need to do so, do not do it.

  [color=#a4885c]10.6[/color] As a Command member, do not put yourself unnecessarily in obviously dangerous situations that go beyond your normal duties and responsibilities, unless in emergency or under great roleplay. For example, as a Captain, you normally should focus on issuing orders and coordinating, not involving yourself directly in combat or pursuing antagonists, and leave that instead to the HoS and Security instead. Doing so in a pinch however, such as trying to help arrest a suspect passing right in front of you, can be allowed.

  [color=#a4885c]10.7[/color] If you are playing a Command role, inform the rest of the Command and your subordinates before cryoing or/and disconnecting.

  [color=#a4885c]10.8[/color] Do not hire your own personal bodyguard yourself. If you want or need one, make a formal request to the HoS for an officer to act as one.
</Document>
