<Document>
[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 6: Erotic-Role-Play (ERP) and NSFW[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c]6.1[/color] Do not kinkshame, nor shame people for resonable provocative or sexual conduct. 

[color=#a4885c]6.2[/color] Furthermore, kinks involving a character pretending to be underage (such as infantilism or ABDL) are also not allowed.

[color=#a4885c]6.3[/color] Any creature and being that is or was not player-controlled (including but not limited to: humanoid NPCs, non-humanoid NPCs, and the corpses of either), is to be considered off-limits for any form of ERP (and roleplay involving controversial, heavy themes). Furthermore, feral creatures must show humanoid-level intelligence in order to be eligible for ERP.

[color=#a4885c]6.4[/color] Roleplay (in speech and in action) of controversial, heavy themes and topics that would make most people uncomfortable, such as self harm, mental health or rape, must be kept out of the public eye and ear and make use of subtle verbs (subtle emote, subtle LOOC, and whisper). Always ensure OOC consent from all parties involved. Ask in AHelp if you are unsure of whether the theme or topic may be a little too extreme to be done openly. Do not make others see or hear unless they want to, and if public, must be done in a subtle, inconspicuous manner.

[color=#a4885c]6.5[/color] Roleplay (in speech and in action) of "extreme" sexual fetishes must be kept out of the public eye and ear and make use of subtle verbs (subtle emote, subtle LOOC, and whisper). Always ensure OOC consent from all parties involved. Ask in AHelp if you are unsure of whether the fetish may be a little too extreme to be done openly. Do not make others see or hear unless they want to, and if public, must be done in a subtle, inconspicuous manner.

[color=#a4885c]6.6[/color] Active ERP must make use of subtle verbs (subtle emote, subtle LOOC, and whisper), unless the area is explicitly sanctioned by admins as a "public ERP area" or is a remote space dedicated to it. Public ERP is allowed, so long it follows this rule and not done in a way that's drawing too much attention or/and forcing others to watch or hear active ERP (for example, going at it full naked on top of the main bar's counter, or exaggerate and go too far with out loud lewd actions to the point it's become active ERP). For ERP involving extreme kinks, the rule before this one must be followed. Do not make others see or hear unless they want to.

[color=#a4885c]6.7[/color] Do not spam or pollute radio channels (including the telepath channel) with NSFW topics, nor exaggerate with loud, public, NSFW talk. Please note that this does not mean you are not allowed to speak or discuss of such. Only overdoing it to the point it's making many people uncomfortable is against the rules. 

[color=#a4885c]6.8[/color] Do not use ERP as bait for kill objectives, unless done with OOC consent of all parties involved. 

[color=#a4885c]6.9[/color] While usage of kinks or sex mechanics for for gameplay or non-sexual roleplay purposes is not forbidden per se, usage of them should still not be done in a way that breaches other rules. Furthermore, involvement of "extreme" kinks still requires the scene to be kept to a private space, and should consider that because of this, certain scenes may inevitably break certain rules. For example, using vore mechanics to hide yourself and your loot from Security, being normally a breach of powergaming and metagaming rules, due to ERP protection etiquette and this forcing others to interact with an extreme kink (resulting in potential consent violations). If you are ever unsure of something, or got a particular idea, ask an Admin via AHelp. Always ensure OOC consent from all parties involved. 

[color=#a4885c]6.10[/color] While it is common etiquette to not directly disturb ERP in progress and ERP areas, in case of necessity, interruptions and disturbances are permitted (for example, Security finding that an antagonist is ERPing with somebody in a dorm and barging in to arrest). This applies especially to Antagonist roles, who should strongly refrain from direct disturbances and interruptions unless absolutely necessary (or unless it's consensual). Indirect disturbances however (i.e. setting off the nuke, cutting power/gravity, taking over the station, etc.), are absolutely permitted. 

</Document>