<Document>
  # Preamble
  [color=#ff0000]WARNING: You MUST be at least 18 years of age to play on Floof Station.[/color]


  [color=#ff0000]Floof Station is an English-based community; use English as your primary method of communication within the game.[/color]


  [color=#ffff00]Rule 0. Admins can disregard any and all of these rules if they deem it in the best interest of the current round, server, and/or community at large. Admins  are held fully accountable for their actions if they exercise this privilege.[/color]


  If you have any questions about these rules, please use the admin help menu by hitting F1 in-game, or clicking the "AHelp" button in the lobby.

  Intentionally disconnecting, responding with hostility, or refusing to respond when an admin privately messages you in Ahelp or a Discord ticket will be met with an appeal-only ban.[/color]

  All AHelp messages are relayed to the Floof Station Discord.

  # Common sense reminders:
  [color=#ffff00]The usage of any applications/scripts/client modifications or any other applicable software to gain an advantage, avoid intended game/server mechanics, or to harm server infrastructure is strictly prohibited, resulting in an unappealable ban, and may additionally result in legal action.[/color]
  [color=#ffff00]Attempting to evade bans will result in an appeal-only ban.[/color]
  [color=#ffff00]Do not Multi-key.[/color]
  [color=#ffff00]Lack of administrator/Centcom response does not equal permission.[/color]
  [color=#ffff00]Security standard operating procedures are meta-shielded, no in-game rule lawyering (Leave it for the lawyers).[/color]

  # Core Rules
  These rules apply at all times, including between rounds.

  Each section contains its own list of rules. Click on the section name to view the full version.

  - [textlink="Section 1. Community Rules" link="RuleC1"]
  - [textlink="Section 2. Gameplay Rules" link="RuleC2"]
  - [textlink="Section 3. Metagaming Rules" link="RuleC3"]
  - [textlink="Section 4. New-life Rules" link="RuleC4"]
  - [textlink="Section 5. Character Naming Rules" link="RuleC5"]
  - [textlink="Section 6. Roleplay Rules" link="RuleC6"]
  - [textlink="Section 7. Powergaming Rules" link="RuleC7"]
  - [textlink="Section 8. End-Of-Round (EOR) Rules" link="RuleC8"]
  - [textlink="Section 9. Erotic-Role-Play (ERP) Rules" link="RuleC9"]
  - [textlink="Section 10. Command and Security Rules" link="RuleC10"]
  - [textlink="Section 11. Antagonist Rules" link="RuleC11"]
</Document>
