<Document>
[head=3][color=#ff0000]WARNING: You must be 18 or older to play. Users under 18 will be banned immediately.[/head][/color]

[color=#99ff99]Floof Station is an English-speaking 18+ adult-only medium roleplay server.[/color] 

[color=#a4885c][head=3]Erotic Roleplay (ERP), erotic content, and 18+ sexual and non-sexual content are allowed on this server.[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c][head=3]Admins may, within reason, act outside of the rules listed below. Admins will be held accountable through use of the admin code of conduct. This mandate, informally known as "Rule 0", is to be used sparingly, for serious situations that otherwise cannot be easily resolved.[/head][/color] 

[color=#ffff00]If you have any questions about these rules, please use the Admin Help menu (AHelp) by pressing the F1 key, or clicking the "AHelp" button on top of your screen (the one with a danger symbol on it).[/color] 

[color=#ffff00]If you are ever unsure of something, or got a particular idea, ask an Admin via AHelp. No response does not equate to permission.[/color] 

Each section contains its own list of rules. Click on the section name to view the full version.

  - [textlink="Section 1. Out Of Character" link="RuleC1"]
  - [textlink="Section 2. Consent" link="RuleC2"]
  - [textlink="Section 3. Metagaming Rules" link="RuleC3"]
  - [textlink="Section 4. Powergaming" link="RuleC4"]
  - [textlink="Section 5. Roleplay and Characters" link="RuleC5"]
  - [textlink="Section 6. Erotic-Role-Play (ERP) and NSFW" link="RuleC6"]
  - [textlink="Section 7. Death and New Life" link="RuleC7"]
  - [textlink="Section 8. End-of-Round (EOR) and Evacuation" link="RuleC8"]
  - [textlink="Section 9. General Roles and Jobs" link="RuleC9"]
  - [textlink="Section 10. Command and Security" link="RuleC10"]
  - [textlink="Section 11. Antagonists" link="RuleC11"]


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 1: Out Of Character[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c]1.1[/color] Be polite, civil and respectful towards other players and admins. Respect their consent, dignity, boundaries, and roleplay preferences. If somebody ever asks you to stop bothering them LOOC (local-out-of-character), do so. Do always bear in mind, that behind every and each player-controlled entity, there is a real person, each with their own feelings, emotions, preferences, and thoughts, and trying to have fun and relax too. 

[color=#a4885c]1.2[/color] Hate speech is forbidden. This applies to both OOC, but also IC interactions. Usage of terms and behavior out of sheer hate or bigotry, will be punished. Playful consensual banter is permitted. 

[color=#a4885c]1.3[/color] Do not ban evade. 

[color=#a4885c]1.4[/color] Do not disconnect during an AHelp in progress (if connection is lost due to Internet issues, open a ticket on the Discord ASAP). 

[color=#a4885c]1.5[/color] Rule lawyering and rule skirting is not tolerated. Neither is ignorance of our rules. Admins get to decide what is good reason, motive and roleplay and what isn't. If you disagree, feel free to open a ticket or an appeal so other admins can review the decision of that one admin. 

[color=#a4885c]1.6[/color] Usage of third party cheat software and exploits is forbidden. 

[color=#a4885c]1.7[/color] Doing anything that may damage server integrity knowingly (i.e. causing lag, the server to crash, server-side glitches, etc.) is strictly forbidden. 

[color=#a4885c]1.8[/color] It is forbidden to livestream rounds to others or share recorded gameplay outside of Floof Station without consent of all parties involved, especially for the purposes of ridiculing, bullying and shaming. 

[color=#a4885c]1.9[/color] Ghosting with the sole intent of spying on other people's personal activities (especially ERP) is not permitted. 

[color=#a4885c]1.10[/color] Do not spam or advertise (either other servers, or in general). 

[color=#a4885c]1.11[/color] Floof Station is meant to be a laid-back environment for all to enjoy, have fun and relax in. We ask people to refrain from or be very mindful about partaking in activities (public or/and towards other players in particular) that would go to the detriment of this atmosphere that we intend to maintain. 


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 2: Consent[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c]2.1[/color] Both roleplay and ERP require all players involved to be consenting, either through IC or OOC means. If your OOC consent is not respected, immediately AHelp or open a ticket. 

[color=#a4885c]2.2[/color] Roleplay may occur under implied consent when all players involved engage in roleplay that suggests mutual willingness with no OOC objections raised during or immediately after the interaction. However, if at any point one of the players expresses discomfort or objects OOC, the roleplay must stop immediately. The same applies to ERP as well. 

[color=#a4885c]2.3[/color] Be mindful of the differences between in-character and out-of-character consent. While roleplay without consent of the character is allowed and not necessarily against the rules, OOC consent is always mandatory and must always be established and clearly ascertained. 

[color=#a4885c]2.4[/color] It is your responsibility to keep your consent preferences up to date. This is especially important in the event some relatively common actions, topics or preferences (i.e. physical contact, sex talk, gender preferences, etc.) are not of your liking, in order to prevent both you from being accidentally upset, and others from needing to walk on eggshells. 

[color=#a4885c]2.5[/color] While usage of kinks or sex mechanics for gameplay or non-sexual roleplay purposes is not forbidden per se, you must seek consent from everybody who may end up or ended up involved in that scene before roleplaying it out. This is especially important in the event "extreme" kinks are involved. 

[color=#a4885c]2.6[/color] For any role involving you taking over the body or/and appearances of somebody else's character, OOC consent from the original (the owner of said character) is mandatory if you mean to engage in ERP or other controversial forms of RP with it. 


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 3: Metagaming[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c]3.1[/color] Do not metagame (i.e. using or sharing information that your character has no way of knowing or obtaining, such as knowledge on the exact loadouts of antagonists, or things seen or heard while dead). 

[color=#a4885c]3.2[/color] Do not use nor share in-character information gained by metacommunication. Discussion about current round is allowed on the Floof Station Discord server. Acting on information gained through this method however is strictly forbidden. 

[color=#a4885c]3.3[/color] Do not metagrudge nor metafriend (i.e. treating unfairly a character solely based on the out of character relationship with the player; or treating them unfairly beyond acceptable and reasonable conduct -for example, attacking on sight- because of previous rounds in-character interactions). 

[color=#a4885c]3.4[/color] Players are allowed to retain and share knowledge of past experiences and prior shifts. However, treating unfairly a character solely based on antagonist-related happenings outside of the current round, is forbidden (for example, treating someone with more or less suspicion or trust solely based on their character being often an antagonist or not). 

[color=#a4885c]3.5[/color] Players are allowed to form in-character relationships (friends, foes, or otherwise). However, providing high profile unfair advantages or disadvantages solely based on those IC relationships, is forbidden (for example, ignoring serious crimes, demoting, barring from services, giving out abnormally high access, handing out normally highly restricted items, etc.). If you are unsure or got a particular idea, ask in AHelp for approval. 

[color=#a4885c]3.6[/color] Use the text channels for their intended purpose (you may "subtle LOOC", namely the usage of the subtle command for private LOOC talk, if the command is unavailable). 


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 4: Powergaming[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c]4.1[/color] Do not powergame (i.e. minmaxing to try and achieve the best possible results to the point of being detrimental to roleplay, rushing to acquire strong or useful equipment you do not need, pulling all sorts meta tricks and exploits that are unfair or unfit for a roleplay environment, and so forth). 

[color=#a4885c]4.2[/color] Do not rush for, hoard, or prepare equipment unrelated to your job or that you do not need. If you, in your given role, require items that do not fall within your job’s usual parameters or that you do not necessarily need, seek in-character roleplay-friendly methods and/or explanations to obtain them and as for why you need or want them. "Greytiding" is allowed so long not performed to an unreasonable degree.

[color=#a4885c]4.3[/color] Manufacturing dangerous, powerful or/and out of the norm items such as weapons, bombs, deadly poisons, specialized machinery, or obstructive structures without reasonable emergency or need, is liable to be considered powergaming behavior. If you are unsure or got a particular idea, ask in AHelp for approval. Seek in-character roleplay-friendly methods and/or explanations to obtain them and as for why you need or want them outside of emergency or strict need.

[color=#a4885c]4.4[/color] As a non-antagonist, do not intentionally hide antagonist objective items, especially in impossible-to-see/access locations. You may hide items somewhere inside of the room they are located in, or on your character. If you are an antagonist, avoid stealing things you do not necessarily need that maybe another antagonist may need. 

[color=#a4885c]4.5[/color] While it is allowed for the crew to know the details around the various antagonist functions, it is forbidden to act on that information without valid motive (for example, evidence strongly suggesting them being an antagonist, or reliable witnesses of a serious crime), and you are always to presume innocence until proven guilty. For example, you shouldn't check PDAs, implants, and headsets, unless there is enough evidence or motive to assume the person is an antagonist. Refer to the SOP for details.

[color=#a4885c]4.6[/color] Do not validhunt (i.e to hunt, pursue, antagonize and otherwise go out of your way to engage an antagonist with hostile intent). Non-Security personnel should not actively seek out and try to attack, detain or kill antagonists and hostile NPCs that are not threatening you immediately. Notable exceptions being, temporary emergency conscription as Security personnel, or endorsement and sanctioning by a Security Officer (or higher, including any Command member as temporary CO in the event Captain, HoS or Warden are KIA) in a serious emergency (for example, rallying the crew to help if most of Security becomes KIA).

[color=#a4885c]4.7[/color] Do not exploit game mechanics, bugs, tricks or unintended features to circumvent roleplay, to make things much easier for you and more unfair for others, or in any malicious capacity. For example, cryo, ghost and death mechanics (i.e antag-rolling, hiding in cryo to escape from Security, etc.). 

[color=#a4885c]4.8[/color] Do not intentionally breach nor metagame roleplay in order to gain unfair advantages (such as, engaging someone in combat when they are busy typing something out directed to you, or fake typing to bait somebody to get closer). 

[color=#a4885c]4.9[/color] Do not dismantle or damage important, irreplaceable station infrastructure. If you are unsure or got a particular idea, ask in AHelp for approval. 

[color=#a4885c]4.10[/color] Try to avoid minmaxing to the point of it becoming a detriment to your job or to roleplay, if not prevent you from doing either or even outright putting people in danger. You don't necessarily need to wait for an advanced ore processor before starting to provide materials to the station as Logistics, and you don't necessarily need to wait for an advanced anomaly vessel before starting to do anomalies as Epistemics. 

[color=#a4885c]4.11[/color] Station departments are expected to be working together and collaborating. Avoid self-isolating "independency" tactics and behaviors (for example, Salvage hoarding what they found instead of distributing the excess, or/and going fully independent, or Epistemics/Logistics acquiring machines that would skip interactions with other departments because it's more "efficient"). 


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 5: Roleplay and Characters[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c]5.1[/color] You are expected to roleplay, and maintain a good level and quality of roleplay. As such, focusing solely on "winning" (such as greentexting) is strongly discouraged. So is questionable behavior unfit for an organized, civilized system and society (such as but not limited to: distribution of highly dangerous items without strict need, emergency or valid motive, casually allowing strangers in your department, casual destruction of station property etc.)

[color=#a4885c]5.2[/color] Prioritize making the game fun for everyone, not just yourself. Security, Command and antagonist roles are held to a higher standard and scrutiny, especially if their actions are found to be going against this rule. Ask an Admin via AHelp if you are unsure of whether or not the idea you got in mind might be pushing too much the acceptable boundaries. 

[color=#a4885c]5.3[/color] Your character is a separate entity from you, the player. Your character's actions, feelings, and knowledge in-game should be based solely on the character's experiences rather than your own as the player. Also, do keep in mind that while your character may be the main character of your story, they are not the protagonist at the center of everything. 

[color=#a4885c]5.4[/color] Do not make yourself a major problem, annoyance, or disruption for the crew while not being an antagonist (i.e. self-antagging or griefing). Examples may include: random murder, destruction or disruption, stealing of high caliber items (such as Security weapons or Command items), or intentional sabotage. 

[color=#a4885c]5.5[/color] Do not play excessively hostile or provocative characters. Playing a character accurately should never result in rule breaches. Being a major nuisance or a source of major frustration to the crew, or behaving in a way that is affecting very negatively the laid-back environment we intend to maintain, is not accepted. If you are unsure or got a particular idea, ask in AHelp for approval. 

[color=#a4885c]5.6[/color] Follow proper escalation (for example, consider assessing a threat for a second before unloading lethal rounds into it, attempt an arrest with non-lethals before opening fire with lethals on someone, and don't use lethal force on someone or something out of the blue without reasonable motive or emergency). Security roles in particular are asked to mind this rule.

[color=#a4885c]5.7[/color] Do not loot AFK players, nor round remove their bodies without consent, outside of reasonable exceptions (biomassing previous bodies of cloned players, Security performing their duties, etc.). 

[color=#a4885c]5.8[/color] Dismantling, scrapping or destruction of station property without a reasonable emergency, urgency or need for it is strongly discouraged (such as for example, dismantling tables and chairs around the station or an escape pod just for its materials and parts).

[color=#a4885c]5.9[/color] Players should always try to bring crew members that are found dead or critically injured to the appropriate department (or to the next best location if unavailable) for treatment, such as Medical or Epistemics. Do not ignore, hide, or destroy their body. This applies for station pets as well, (the animals with unique names, and friendly creatures who are given pet status by the HoP), who are also considered as part of the crew. 

[color=#a4885c]5.10[/color] If, when and where possible, always try to do things in a roleplay-friendly way and keep the roleplay rolling. For example, for controversial matters (such as firing an Head), consider contacting CentCom first before immediately AHelping (unless it's for a major rule violation, or unless you are not receiving any answer back from CentCom). 

[color=#a4885c]5.11[/color] Players are allowed and even encouraged to engage in creative gimmicks, mischief, hijinks and ideas, so long it doesn't cross the border into unacceptable behavior (self-antag, powergaming, metagaming, etc.) and so long properly and well roleplayed. Examples of acceptable ideas could be, light greytiding, well roleplayed hooliganism, breaking into places with good RP or motive, thievery, or black marketing. 

[color=#a4885c]5.12[/color] When picking the name for a character, give them a believable name (and surname if applicable), or a believable nickname to go by. Do not make obvious references, puns, or plays on words. You may "cosplay" a fictional character, but you cannot be the character. Leeway is given to theatrical roles such as the clown, boxer, and mime; these roles are allowed stage names with some more freedom. 


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 6: Erotic-Role-Play (ERP) and NSFW[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c]6.1[/color] Do not kinkshame, nor shame people for resonable provocative or sexual conduct. 

[color=#a4885c]6.2[/color] Furthermore, kinks involving a character pretending to be underage (such as infantilism or ABDL) are also not allowed.

[color=#a4885c]6.3[/color] Any creature and being that is or was not player-controlled (including but not limited to: humanoid NPCs, non-humanoid NPCs, and the corpses of either), is to be considered off-limits for any form of ERP (and roleplay involving controversial, heavy themes). Furthermore, feral creatures must show humanoid-level intelligence in order to be eligible for ERP.

[color=#a4885c]6.4[/color] Roleplay (in speech and in action) of controversial, heavy themes and topics that would make most people uncomfortable, such as self harm, mental health or rape, must be kept out of the public eye and ear and make use of subtle verbs (subtle emote, subtle LOOC, and whisper). Always ensure OOC consent from all parties involved. Ask in AHelp if you are unsure of whether the theme or topic may be a little too extreme to be done openly. Do not make others see or hear unless they want to, and if public, must be done in a subtle, inconspicuous manner.

[color=#a4885c]6.5[/color] Roleplay (in speech and in action) of "extreme" sexual fetishes must be kept out of the public eye and ear and make use of subtle verbs (subtle emote, subtle LOOC, and whisper). Always ensure OOC consent from all parties involved. Ask in AHelp if you are unsure of whether the fetish may be a little too extreme to be done openly. Do not make others see or hear unless they want to, and if public, must be done in a subtle, inconspicuous manner.

[color=#a4885c]6.6[/color] Active ERP must make use of subtle verbs (subtle emote, subtle LOOC, and whisper), unless the area is explicitly sanctioned by admins as a "public ERP area" or is a remote space dedicated to it. Public ERP is allowed, so long it follows this rule and not done in a way that's drawing too much attention or/and forcing others to watch or hear active ERP (for example, going at it full naked on top of the main bar's counter, or exaggerate and go too far with out loud lewd actions to the point it's become active ERP). For ERP involving extreme kinks, the rule before this one must be followed. Do not make others see or hear unless they want to.

[color=#a4885c]6.7[/color] Do not spam or pollute radio channels (including the telepath channel) with NSFW topics, nor exaggerate with loud, public, NSFW talk. Please note that this does not mean you are not allowed to speak or discuss of such. Only overdoing it to the point it's making many people uncomfortable is against the rules. 

[color=#a4885c]6.8[/color] Do not use ERP as bait for kill objectives, unless done with OOC consent of all parties involved. 

[color=#a4885c]6.9[/color] While usage of kinks or sex mechanics for for gameplay or non-sexual roleplay purposes is not forbidden per se, usage of them should still not be done in a way that breaches other rules. Furthermore, involvement of "extreme" kinks still requires the scene to be kept to a private space, and should consider that because of this, certain scenes may inevitably break certain rules. For example, using vore mechanics to hide yourself and your loot from Security, being normally a breach of powergaming and metagaming rules, due to ERP protection etiquette and this forcing others to interact with an extreme kink (resulting in potential consent violations). If you are ever unsure of something, or got a particular idea, ask an Admin via AHelp. Always ensure OOC consent from all parties involved. 

[color=#a4885c]6.10[/color] While it is common etiquette to not directly disturb ERP in progress and ERP areas, in case of necessity, interruptions and disturbances are permitted (for example, Security finding that an antagonist is ERPing with somebody in a dorm and barging in to arrest). This applies especially to Antagonist roles, who should strongly refrain from direct disturbances and interruptions unless absolutely necessary (or unless it's consensual). Indirect disturbances however (i.e. setting off the nuke, cutting power/gravity, taking over the station, etc.), are absolutely permitted. 


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 7: Death and New Life[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c]7.1[/color] Players maintain all in character memory up until the point of going into their unconscious/critical health state. 

[color=#a4885c]7.2[/color] If a player is brought back to life by any means that is not cloning or similar, they may only retain vague details of the events leading up to their death, and none in relation to the killer, their method, and how it specifically went down. For example, if hypopenned or stabbed to death, they may remember stinging, but not specifically that they got hypopenned or stabbed, nor by who. If they died by a poisoned burger, they may remember eating a burger. If they got killed by a nukie after knowing already a nukie is on board, they can easily assume they got killed by said nukie, but only have a vague recollection of the details leading up to their death. 

[color=#a4885c]7.3[/color] If a player is brought back to life by means of cloning (or similar methods implying new life in a new brain), they lose all of the memories that have been acquired so far into shift. 

[color=#a4885c]7.4[/color] Characters do not retain any knowledge of what happened while they were dead. As such, usage and/or in-character relaying of information gained while dead is forbidden and also considered a metagaming violation. 

[color=#a4885c]7.5[/color] Characters only retain vague memories of what happened while in a critical state, asleep, or generally unconscious (i.e. remembering hearing the radio crackle while asleep, remembering feeling their PDA being touched while crit, etc.). 

[color=#a4885c]7.6[/color] 7.6 If your character dies or enters cryostasis beyond the point of no return, you normally cannot respawn as the same character. Seek permission from an admin if you need or wish to do so. The only allowed exception being, if you accidentally spawn as the wrong character or job, and so immediately cryo to rejoin with the right one. At this moment, personnel recovery forms are also accepted if submitted to CC as a way for other players to ask admins to allow a character to respawn.


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 8: End-of-Round (EOR) and Evacuation[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c]8.1[/color] Disruptive behavior in end-of-round Safe Havens (such as the evacuation shuttle and Central Command) is forbidden. This includes but is not limited to: damaging property, intentionally blocking pathways to prevent other players from passing through, fighting, etc. During evacuation or crew transfer, the evacuation boarding areas and hallways directly next to the evacuation shuttle are considered part of the Safe Haven as well. 

[color=#a4885c]8.2[/color] Conflicts in End-Of-Round Safe Havens must remain verbal and non-violent. Exception is made for Security, who may perform arrests non-lethally. 

[color=#a4885c]8.3[/color] In a Safe Haven, lethal force may only be used for threats that cannot be stopped in any other way. This generally only applies to hostile NPCs and self defense. 

[color=#a4885c]8.4[/color] Antagonist roles are allowed to pursue non-violent objectives in a non-violent way in Safe Havens. However, if caught, they must not resist arrest and surrender. 

[color=#a4885c]8.5[/color] Evac should be called or recalled based on either general public consensus, or under whether a major, serious emergency is being deemed as solvable or not. Forcefully calling or recalling without reasonable urgency, emergency or need is not allowed. Consider calling ERT, CBURN or other such entities first, and if you receive no response or they fail as well, proceed to call evac. For example, calling evac just because Nukies showed up is bad practice, but serious hard to repair structural damage to the station or most Security becoming KIA, are pretty sound motives.

[color=#a4885c]8.6[/color] Antagonists are not allowed to call nor recall evac. Intentionally disrupting evac, such as parking or hovering a ship at or near the area where normally evac arrives for the purpose of forcing evac to dock elsewhere, is not allowed. Some exceptions may be allowed, but require explicit administrator approval. 


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 9: General Roles and Jobs[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c]9.1[/color] If you choose a job on shift, you are required to participate in the round as said job when necessary. If you are requested or needed, you must respond or return to your duties ASAP. Do not ignore calls or emergencies. ERP does not take priority over your job. This is especially important for Command and Security jobs. 

[color=#a4885c]9.2[/color] If you are banned from a role or a department, you may not play that role or job. This includes seeking or accepting promotions into roles you are banned from, and taking ghost roles allowing you to play out the job or role in question. 

[color=#a4885c]9.3[/color] Try not to engage in tasks that do not fall under the purview of your job. Doing something in a pinch is alright, and so is helping out someone that you see is struggling a bit. But otherwise, let each role do their job. Exceptions can be made for emergencies, during severe personnel shortages in a department, and for some Service duties (for example, playing music at bar in place of the musician, bartend for central bars despite not being a bartender, or cleaning your department yourself). 

[color=#a4885c]9.4[/color] By picking the prisoner/gladiator role, you have chosen to roleplay as a prisoner/gladiator, NOT an antagonist, and you should not act as such in any capacity. This includes (but is not limited to) any attempt at breaking out without reasonable emergency or need or admin approval, staging riots, or killing Security or fellow prisoners (obvious exception being, gladiator fights to the death).

[color=#a4885c]9.5[/color] Ghost roles have their own independent rules that must be followed. 

[color=#a4885c]9.6[/color] Department strikes (i.e. Cargonia and any variation thereof), riots, cults, and any other such events, require explicit administrator approval. 


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 10: Command and Security[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c]10.1[/color] Security and Command roles must know how to perform their job to the best of their ability, and are held to a higher standard of roleplay. This does not mean they must roleplay strict and realistic, but merely that higher quality roleplay, skill and sensible reasoning is expected. 

[color=#a4885c]10.2[/color] Command, and especially Security, are required to know Security Standard Operating Procedures, Alert Procedure, and Company Policy, and are expected to try and follow them to the best of their abilities. Some leniency is given to: Cadets, in reason of it being a learning role; general breaches performed in dire emergency (plus minor general breaches happening under good quality roleplay); and Company Policy, some parts of which do not necessarily need to be strictly followed (such as dressing code, formalities and the likes). 

[color=#a4885c]10.3[/color] Do not abuse your position of power (unless this is being done privately and with consent of all parties involved). 

[color=#a4885c]10.4[/color] As a Command member, you are to adhere to your responsibilities and duties. Prioritize the needs and wants of the station, not only those of your own or of your friends. This especially applies during emergencies and crisis situations. 

[color=#a4885c]10.5[/color] Use lethals and lethal force within reason. As per SOP, arrest with non-lethals if possible, proceed with lethals if not. If you do not have a reasonable urgency, emergency or need to do so, do not do it.

[color=#a4885c]10.6[/color] As a Command member, do not put yourself unnecessarily in obviously dangerous situations that go beyond your normal duties and responsibilities, unless in emergency or under great roleplay. For example, as a Captain, you normally should focus on issuing orders and coordinating, not involving yourself directly in combat or pursuing antagonists, and leave that instead to the HoS and Security instead. Doing so in a pinch however, such as trying to help arrest a suspect passing right in front of you, can be allowed. 

[color=#a4885c]10.7[/color] If you are playing a Command role, inform the rest of the Command and your subordinates before cryoing or/and disconnecting. 

[color=#a4885c]10.8[/color] Do not hire your own personal bodyguard yourself. If you want or need one, make a formal request to the HoS for an officer to act as one. 


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 11: Antagonists[/head][/color] 

[color=#a4885c]11.1[/color] Antagonistic roles are held to a higher standard of roleplay. 

[color=#a4885c]11.2[/color] Damage by any antagonist role must be proportional to their related objectives, and be pertinent to their objectives. Rarely if ever, station-wide destruction and mass killing is justifiable. Ask an Admin via AHelp if you are unsure of whether the level of damage you want to cause is acceptable or not. 

[color=#a4885c]11.3[/color] Antagonists must follow a 30 minutes grace period from round start. 

[color=#a4885c]11.4[/color] Playing a normally hostile ghost role as a friendly is permitted. However, it is strongly advised to seek permission from an admin if you wish to do so. This way, the admin may help in clarifying your friendly status. Else, you will be liable for being killed or attacked on sight (so long of course proper escalation, reasoning and roleplay is followed by the attacker). Furthermore, by making this choice, you are forbidden from switching back to playing it as an hostile role without extremely good motive, and are also forbidden from faking being friendly. 

[color=#a4885c]11.5[/color] Intentional round removal is forbidden, kill objectives being the only exception to this rule. 

[color=#a4885c]11.6[/color] The role of an antagonist is to make the game more fun, exciting and interesting, not miserable, unfun and frustrating. As such, try to play out the role accordingly, focusing not on winning, but on making things more thrilling and entertaining. 

[color=#a4885c]11.7[/color] Antagonists should refrain from collaborating unless they belong to the same faction and do have an actual mutual deal established. For example, a nuclear operative and an agent may collaborate, so long within terms such as, an operative helping an agent to complete one or more objectives, and in turn them helping with acquiring the nuke and the disk (but not staying behind after countdown begins to ensure it goes off, since the nuke is not their primary objective and they should be coming back alive).
</Document>