<Document>
[head=3][color=#ff0000]WARNING: You must be 18 or older to play. Users under 18 will be banned immediately.[/head][/color]

[color=#99ff99]Floof Station is an english speaking adult 18+ medium roleplay server[/color]

[color=#a4885c][head=3]0. Implimentation and interpretation of the rules is up to the sole discretion of the Mods.[/head][/color]
	
	• Mods will instead be held accountable through use of the Moderator code of conduct. 

[color=#a4885c][head=3]0.1 Erotic Roleplay (ERP), erotic content, or 18+ sexual content is allowed on this server.[/head][/color]

[color=#ffff00]If you have any questions about these rules, please use the Moderator help menu by hitting F1 in-game, or clicking the "AHelp" button in the lobby.[/color]

  # Core Rules
  These rules apply at all times, including between rounds.

  Each section contains its own list of rules. Click on the section name to view the full version.

  - [textlink="Section 1. Behavioral Rules" link="RuleC1"]
  - [textlink="Section 2. Gameplay Rules" link="RuleC2"]
  - [textlink="Section 3. Metagaming Rules" link="RuleC3"]
  - [textlink="Section 4. New-life Rules" link="RuleC4"]
  - [textlink="Section 5. Character Naming Rules" link="RuleC5"]
  - [textlink="Section 6. Roleplay Rules" link="RuleC6"]
  - [textlink="Section 7. Powergaming Rules" link="RuleC7"]
  - [textlink="Section 8. End-Of-Round (EOR) Rules" link="RuleC8"]
  - [textlink="Section 9. Erotic-Role-Play (ERP) Rules" link="RuleC9"]
  - [textlink="Section 10. Command and Security Rules" link="RuleC10"]
  - [textlink="Section 11. Antagonist Rules" link="RuleC11"]
  
  [color=#ffff00][head=3]Severity guidelines:[/head][/color]
	
	• *1
	
	Minor infraction
	
	•[color=#f1c232]*2[/color]
	
	Major infraction
	
	•[color=#cc0000]*3[/color]
	
	Extreme infraction
	
[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 1: Behavior Rules[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]1.1[/color] Be respectful to others OOC. *1

[color=#a4885c]1.2[/color] Don't use hate speech, racism, or bigoted comments. *1 

[color=#a4885c]1.3[/color] Don't metagame. *1	

[color=#a4885c]1.4[/color] Don't spam or advertise. *1

[color=#a4885c]1.5[/color] Do not intentionally take actions that would negatively impact or disrupt others enjoyment of the game. *1

[color=#a4885c]1.6[/color][color=#f1c232] Avoid controversial topics such as self harm/rape in public. *2 [/color]

[color=#a4885c]1.7[/color][color=#f1c232] Don't evade bans. *2 [/color]

[color=#a4885c]1.8[/color][color=#f1c232] Don't self antag. *2 [/color]

[color=#a4885c]1.9[/color][color=#f1c232] Don't ragequit/disconnect to avoid consequences. *2 [/color]

[color=#a4885c]1.10[/color][color=#cc0000] Cheating and exploits are forbidden. *3 [/color]

[color=#a4885c]1.11[/color][color=#cc0000] Respect others consent preferences. *3 [/color]


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 2: Game Server Rules[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]2.1[/color] [color=#f1c232]If you are banned from a role or department, you may not play that role. This includes seeking or accepting promotions into roles you are banned from or taking Ghost roles which hold the role in question. *2[/color]

[color=#a4885c]2.2[/color] [color=#f1c232]Do not make yourself a major problem, annoyance, or disruption for the crew while not being an antagonist (i.e. self-antagging). *2[/color]

[color=#a4885c]2.3[/color] [color=#f1c232]Department strikes (e.g. cargonia and any variation thereof), riots, cults require explicit administrator approval. *2[/color]

[color=#a4885c]2.4[/color] [color=#f1c232]It is strictly forbidden to livestream rounds to others or share recorded gameplay outside of Floofstation without consent of all parties involved. *2[/color]

[color=#a4885c]2.5[/color] [color=#f1c232]Ghosting with with the sole intent of spying on others personal activities is not permitted. *2[/color]


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 3: Metagaming Rules[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]3.1[/color] Use the chat channels for their intended purpose. *1

[color=#a4885c]3.2[/color] Characters do not retain any knowledge of what happened while they were dead. *1

[color=#a4885c]3.3[/color] Do not emote gore or deathrattles. *1

[color=#a4885c]3.4[/color] Do not use any information gained by meta-communication. *1

[color=#a4885c]3.5[/color] Discussion about the current round is allowed on the Floof Station Discord server. Acting on information gained through this method is forbidden. *1

[color=#a4885c]3.6[/color] Do not meta-grudge or meta-friend. You are allowed to have knowledge of past experiences and prior shifts, and players are allowed to have in-character relationships (friends, enemies, or otherwise). *1

[color=#a4885c]3.7[/color] Do NOT antag-roll. *1

[color=#a4885c]3.8[/color] Do NOT cryo for the purpose of playing a ghost antagonist role. *1


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 4: New-Life Rules[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]4.1[/color] Players maintain all in character memory up until the point of going into their unconscious/critical health state. *1

[color=#a4885c]4.2[/color] If a player is brought back to life they lose the last 5 minutes of memory before death. *1

[color=#a4885c][head=3]Section 5: Naming Rules[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]5.1[/color] Don't make references. Obvious puns or plays on words. *1

Try to be creative by picking a believable and fitting name and/or surname.

Leeway is given to theatrical roles such as the clown, boxer, and mime; these roles are allowed stage names with some freedom.

[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 6: Roleplay Rules[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]6.1[/color] Your character is a separate entity from you, the player. Your character's actions, feelings, and knowledge in-game should be based solely on the character's experiences rather than your own as the player. *1

[color=#a4885c]6.2[/color] Do not play excessively hostile or provocative characters. Playing a character accurately should never result in rulebreaks.  - Ahelp for any questions relating to this. *1

[color=#a4885c]6.3[/color] If someone is critically injured, players should seek medical help for them, if they die, do not destroy or hide their body. *1

[color=#a4885c]6.4[/color] Non-security personnel should only seek to confront threats in the event they find their life is in immediate danger. *1

[color=#a4885c]6.5[/color] If you choose a job on shift, you are required to participate in the round as said job when necessary. *1

[color=#a4885c]6.6[/color] Do not intentionally break roleplay to gain an unfair advantage while someone is typing. *1

[color=#a4885c]6.7[/color][color=#f1c232] Respect other people's consent, dignity and boundaries. IF SOMEBODY ASKS YOU TO STOP BOTHERING THEM LOOC (local-out-of-character), do so. If this rule is abused, Ahelp right away. *2[/color]

[color=#a4885c]6.8[/color][color=#f1c232] By picking the prisoner/gladiator role, you have chosen to roleplay as a prisoner/gladiator, NOT an antagonist, and should not act so in any capacity. *2[/color]

[color=#a4885c]6.9[/color][color=#f1c232] Do not dismantle key portions of station infrastructure (IE. escape pods.) *2[/color]


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 7: Powergaming Rules[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]7.1[/color] Don't rush for or prepare equipment unrelated to your job. If you, in your given role, require an item that does not fall within your job’s usual parameters, seek in-character RP methods to obtain them. *1

[color=#a4885c]7.2[/color] Manufacturing weapons, bombs, deadly poisons, or structures before you know of any reason you would need them for is powergaming behavior. *1

[color=#a4885c]7.3[/color] Do not hide Antag objective items. *1

[color=#a4885c]7.4[/color] Do NOT, under any circumstances, hide the nuclear fission explosive or the authentication disk in an impossible-to-see/access location. *1

[color=#a4885c]7.5[/color] While it is allowed for the crew to know the details around the various antagonist functions, it is strictly forbidden from acting on that information without valid reason and suspicion, and you are always to presume innocence until proven guilty. For example, you shouldn't check PDAs, implants, and headsets, unless the person is strongly suspected to be a syndicate agent, and there is evidence to back this up. *1

[color=#a4885c]7.6[/color] Do not make active use of known bugs in the game. *1


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 8: End-of-Round (EOR) Rules[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]8.1[/color] End-of-round-griefing (EORG) is not allowed under any circumstance. This includes but is not limited to: fighting, explosives, chemicals, destruction of property, or any other disruptive behavior. *1

[color=#a4885c]8.2[/color] Central command as well as the Evac shuttle (and evac hallway) are considered Safezones in which this rule takes effect. *1


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 9: Erotic-Role-Play (ERP) Rules[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]9.1[/color] Make your consent menu specific. Include information such as Gender preferences, sexual orientation, kinks you like or dislike, non negotiable as well as any non sexual physical contact preferences. *1

[color=#a4885c]9.2[/color] ERP does not take priority over your job. If you are requested or needed, you must respond or return to your duties ASAP. *1

[color=#a4885c]9.3[/color] DO NOT use ERP as bait for kill objectives, unless done with OOC consent of all parties involved. After the ERP is complete, a grace period of 5 minutes is in effect, during which you are still NOT allowed to kill the target. *1

[color=#a4885c]9.4[/color] Do not kinkshame. *1

[color=#a4885c]9.5[/color] You MUST use the (-) subtle command for any and all erotic roleplay material. *1

[color=#a4885c]9.6[/color] Do not spam or pollute radio channels (including the telepath channel) with NSFW topics. Mind you, this does NOT mean that you are not allowed to speak or discuss such. There should not be a cringy spamfest of: shitposting, hornyposting, or depression posting. *1

[color=#a4885c]9.7[/color] Do not engage in, nor discuss, ‘extreme’ sexual fetishes in public. Public includes: any radio channel (including the telepath channel), out loud speech or overt actions in actual public physical locations, or doing so on camera. *1

[color=#a4885c]9.8[/color][color=#f1c232] Engaging in ERP with a non-sentient creature is prohibited. The creature must be player-controlled; consent in OOC, and pass the Harkness test in character. *2[/color]

[color=#a4885c]9.9[/color][color=#f1c232] As a Paradox anomaly, OOC consent from the original (the owner of said character) is required before you engage in ERP. *2[/color]

[color=#a4885c]9.10[/color][color=#cc0000] Roleplaying a character as underage is strictly forbidden. So is talk of such activities. *3[/color]

[color=#a4885c]9.11[/color][color=#cc0000] Be very mindful of in-character and out-of-character consent. If your (out-of-character) OOC consent is not respected, immediately Ahelp or open a ticket. *3[/color]

[color=#a4885c]9.12[/color][color=#cc0000] Extreme acts like snuff, abuse, noncon, and other extreme kinks are only allowed if all parties consented OOC, Ahelp if you need clarification (Keep it private). *3[/color]


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 10: Command and Security Rules[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]10.1[/color] Security and Command roles are expected to know and perform their jobs to the best of their ability. You will be held to a higher standard in these roles. *1

[color=#a4885c]10.2[/color] Both Security and Command are required to Know Floof Station Space Law, Standard Operating Procedures, Alert Procedure, and Company Policy. *1

[color=#a4885c]10.3[/color] Don't abuse your position of power. *1

[color=#a4885c]10.4[/color] You are expected to roleplay with others, this includes antagonists. *1

[color=#a4885c]10.5[/color] From round start Security is expected to follow a 30 minute grace period. *1

[color=#a4885c]10.6[/color] If you're in command, inform the rest of the command before disconnecting. *1


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 11: Antagonist Guidelines[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]11.1[/color] Antagonists are held to a higher standard, similar to Command. *1

[color=#a4885c]11.2[/color] Antagonists are expected to roleplay with others, this includes Security and Command. *1

[color=#a4885c]11.3[/color] The damage that an antagonist is allowed to cause must be proportional to their objectives. *1

[color=#a4885c]11.4[/color] From round start Antagonists are expected to follow a 30 minute grace period. *1

[color=#a4885c]11.5[/color] Ghost roles have their own independent rules that must be followed. *1
</Document>
