<Document>
  # Quadborgs
  Quadborgs are the quadruped variant of [textlink="cyborgs" link="Cyborgs"]. They function virtually the same, and are also bound by [color=cyan]silicon law.[/color] The only major differences are the material cost, appearance, ability to serve in the security department as a silicon, and lack of a Generic, Janitorial, and Engineering chassis.

  ## Endoskeleton
  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Quadborgendoskeleton" Caption="Quadborg Endoskeleton"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ExosuitFabricator" Caption="Exosuit Fabricator"/>
  </Box>
  All quadborgs start off as a [color=#a4885c]four-legged[/color] endoskeleton. Much like the cyborg endoskeleton, this is crafted at the [color=#a4885c]Exosuit Fabricator[/color], and uses cyborg parts. Assembly steps can be followed by [color=#a4885c]examining[/color] the endoskeleton. While assembly is similiar, [bold]Quadborgs do not have arms, and instead utilize two right legs, and two left legs as part of it's construction.[/bold]
    
  Once built, further upgrades such as additional tooling and better power cells can be installed later on.
    
  ## Chassis
  Quadborg chassis are similiar in function to the cyborg chassis, bearing the same nuances revolving [color=#a4885c]radio communication[/color] and [color=#a4885c]all-access[/color] except command areas. [bold]Quadborg chassis can fit up to 4 modules, with exception to the Service chassis which while it can fit 4 modules, it has some built in modules as well,[/bold] made possible from it's [italic]"auxillary hardware"[/italic] purpose-built for it.
  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgChassisQuadserv" Caption="Service" Rotation="270"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgChassisQuad" Caption="Security" Rotation="270"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgChassisQuadsalv" Caption="Salvage" Rotation="270"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgChassisQuadmed" Caption="Medical" Rotation="270"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
  [italic]Examples of various quadborg chassis[/italic]
  </Box>
  If you wish to change the chassis of an already existing quadborg, you have to construct a whole new one, parts and endoskeleton included. The brain, power cell and modules [italic](if it can fit in the new chassis,)[/italic] can be carried over from the old chassis, if desired.

  ## Security Applications
  Unique to quadborgs is the capability to serve in the security department as a silicon. [bold]Using generic cyborg parts on a quadborg endoskeleton will construct the security chassis.[/bold]
  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgChassisQuad" Caption="Security Quadborg" Rotation="270"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SecurityTechFab" Caption="Security TechFab"/>
  </Box>
  The security chassis can only be unlocked by security, command, or another borg. Epistemics personnel will not be able to unlock the chassis due to access restrictions. [italic](Afterall, it can fit weapons!)[/italic]

  [color=#a4885c]Security cyborg modules[/color] can only be manufactured at the [color=#a4885c]security techfab[/color]. Make sure to notify your newly commissioned security quadborg of this fact to avoid confusion.
  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModuleStun" Caption="Disabler"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModuleInvestigation" Caption="Investigation"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModuleKill" Caption="Combat"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
  [italic]Examples of security cyborg modules. Note the housing and circuit board colors.[/italic]
  </Box>
</Document>
